<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://www.chrisyin.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.chrisyin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 23:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hatsune Miku</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/04/hatsune-miku/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/04/hatsune-miku</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, a friend of mine showed me &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hatsune_Miku&quot;&gt;Hatsune Miku&lt;/a&gt;, the famous Japanese virtual pop star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s a digital image of a 16 year old female cartoon. Somebody writes the lyrics, does the animations, and she is the public face of all of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s incredibly popular - not just millions of Youtube views, but also tons of sold out live concerts. She’s more prolific than any other singer – over 22,000 original songs and featured in over 100,000 others. And needless to say, she makes money hand over fist. Recently she even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/ryanhatesthis/who-the-heck-is-hatsune-miku&quot;&gt;came to Letterman&lt;/a&gt; to perform. Take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' frameborder='0' height='400' src='//www.youtube.com/embed/rL5YKZ9ecpg' width='532'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460&quot;&gt;software eats the world&lt;/a&gt;, fascinating to watch this applied to music. Will be interesting to continue watching this unfold and see software continue to eat more things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Remote Working Is Still Hard</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/02/remote-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/02/remote-working</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/remote.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;remote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a global company, we have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupa.com/our-offices&quot;&gt;several remote offices and people&lt;/a&gt;. I used to be one of them – lived in San Diego, HQ in San Mateo. And I’ve always thought that the tools we use to bridge gap felt suboptimal. In speaking to other remote people, they feel the same way – there’s something missing for remote workers. I touched on it slightly &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/10/01/collaboration/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While remote working is taking hold in companies, it is still feels secondary to in person working. This applies to the tools we have today – they feel like extensions of in person collaboration as opposed to being built for a remote working first organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools for modern remote working are typically some means of communication and sharing. So we use Hipchat for chat, Jira as a dev tracker, Zendesk as a support tracker, Google Drive for docs/spreadsheets, Github for code, Gmail and more. An absurd number of tools, and the noise that comes out of all this is very hard to wade through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re getting barraged with emails, pinged on Hipchat, Jira/Zendesk tickets getting assigned to you – it’s nearly impossible to figure out what is important and what is not. These tools facilitate one to many communication – leading to a tendency to spam people. Safer to add someone than not, making an already noisy workplace noisier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In person, you gain context &amp;amp; focus. Very easy to see the current context and gauge if it’s a good time to ask someone for some focused time. And if they’ve agreed, very easy to determine whether or not you’re getting it – both if it’s a 5 min sync up or an hour long session. On the web it’s not so easy to tell who’s busy or not – and if you do get their time, if they’re focused or not. This coupled with the spammy nature of our tools drives a wedge between in person workers and remotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second missing aspect is visibility. On the web, you’re as good as your chat icon status and how you often you communicate what you’re doing. In person, people can physically see you in the office, even if they don’t talk to you. Remotely it’s much more difficult to get visibility and recognition, which is an important part of working on a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve seen some of these tools work in a 100% remote environment. In a 100% remote environment, everyone respects the rules of remote tools – always online, responsive, status up to date, efficient communication, etc. It works – &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.hbr.org/2013/03/how-wordpress-thrives-with-a-1/&quot;&gt;Automattic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.bufferapp.com/remote-working-means-tools-use/&quot;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/blog/how-manage-remote-team/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; are good examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s when there is a mix between remotes and in person that this break down. Not everyone lives online, and so the tools aren’t being used properly. If the tools fail, those in person can always default to ‘I’ll catch them in the office tomorrow’. This breakes the integrity of these tools and ultimately fails remote workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a great solution, but I do think things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqwiggle.com/&quot;&gt;Sqwiggle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://idonethis.com/&quot;&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt; are on the right path. We need tools to help gain context &amp;amp; focus (Sqwiggle does a great job of this with easy, near always on video chat) as well as a way to increase visibility (iDonethis) &amp;amp; camraderie in our tools. The key in a mixed organization is for everyone to adopt the tools, not just remote workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Videos in Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/01/youtube-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/11/01/youtube-jekyll</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was trying to embed Youtube videos onto my blog (Jekyll / Markdown), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10529859/how-to-include-video-in-jekyll-markdown-blog&quot;&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.pibby.com/jekyll-youtube-plugin/&quot;&gt;of the ways&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/vanto/1455726&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.omgmog.net/post/video-integration-with-jekyll/&quot;&gt;out there&lt;/a&gt; weren’t working for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless what I did, I always hit this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Maruku cannot parse this block of HTML/XML: 
# &amp;lt;iframe 
     width=&amp;quot;532&amp;quot; 
     height=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; 
     src=&amp;quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iqUG2_cmZ6I&amp;quot; 
     frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; 
     allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trying a bunch, what eventually what did work was 2 things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that there’s a space between the opening and closing iframe tags.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And change &lt;code&gt;allowfullscreen&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;allowfullscreen=&amp;quot;allowfullscreen&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the above should look like below. Thanks internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
# &amp;lt;iframe 
     width=&amp;quot;532&amp;quot; 
     height=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; 
     src=&amp;quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iqUG2_cmZ6I&amp;quot; 
     frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; 
     allowfullscreen=&amp;quot;allowfullscreen&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BrightEyes Fireside Chat</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/29/brighteyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/29/brighteyes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did a chat with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/diplateevo&quot;&gt;Daniel Kao&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brighteyes-students.org/&quot;&gt;BrightEyes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talked about startup, Xpenser, Coupa, and more. Was fun to do this, video embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' frameborder='0' height='400' src='//www.youtube.com/embed/lUPOfTd-RnE' width='532'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooms</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/25/rooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/25/rooms</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rooms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rooms&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joshm&quot;&gt;Josh Miller&lt;/a&gt; just released a new app called Rooms. The intent is to create a place where you can chat and share images in different topic based rooms. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rooms.me/&quot;&gt;Check it out here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh comes from created &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.com/&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;, backed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://obvious.com&quot;&gt;Obvious&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook then &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/13/facebook-acquires-branch/&quot;&gt;acquired them&lt;/a&gt;, this product makes a lot of sense for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly really well done and a fun app to play with, I haven’t found great utility with it yet. I don’t see a problem or purpose for it, and the general sentiment has been similar – do we really need another place to chat about nonsense? I’m not convinced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is an interesting piece in the app. Each chat room in the app has a QR code attached to it. And in order to join any room, you need to scan it – either via camera or through a screenshot (screenshot the QR code, and upload it). First time I’ve seen this particular interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rooms-qr.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;rooms-qr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2014/10/facebook-rooms-app/&quot;&gt;Wired post&lt;/a&gt;, Josh explains that joining rooms is a core part of the app – but while sharing links is native on the web, it’s not easy on mobile. On mobile, images are the native form of data. So they created this new way to share rooms – QR codes on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved the thought process and the experimentation here, hope to see more of this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Online Education</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/13/on-online-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/13/on-online-learning</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/collegeclassroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;collegeclassroom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently chatting with a friend of mine, &lt;a href=&quot;http://diplateevo.com/&quot;&gt;Daniel Kao&lt;/a&gt;, about online learning – sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/&quot;&gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise of these &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course&quot;&gt;online learning sites (MOOC’s)&lt;/a&gt; is to bring university level content to the world via the web. You can now take a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/cs101&quot;&gt;Stanford CS course online&lt;/a&gt; for free, from anywhere in the world. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have personally learned a tremendous amount on MOOC’s. But I’m still skeptical of their ability to make a material impact on what we think of today as education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When MOOC’s came about, like most people, I got super excited and signed up for every interesting class that I saw. And like most people, I signed up for far more courses than I actually completed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2013/05/10/new-study-low-mooc-completion-rates&quot;&gt;Completion rates for MOOC’s are dismally low&lt;/a&gt; and the general population does not yet respect an education from a MOOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional education is a lengthy, structured process in which we trade our time &amp;amp; money for the promise of jobs. There are 2 main types of learners – the full time student &amp;amp; the hobbyist learner. The full time student is making a long-term investment to eventually translate classes to a job. The hobbyist learner is doing the same, just on a shorter timeframe – learn immediate skills to get promoted, get a new job, start a side gig, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOOC’s solve neither problem. For full time students, a certificate of completion from a MOOC is not respected by companies. For the hobbyist learner, these classes are too theoretical and abstract to translate into immediate value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until MOOC’s can figure out how to help users more concretely translate time investment to value, they will continue to be treated as an educational supplement at best. Not to mention that online courses don’t yet take into account non-academic learnings of school – social skills, networking, etc. These are equally important, and are a large reason why in-school education is still so valued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few new takes of learning that are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is vertical learning as a supplement to traditional education. Dev Bootcamp is a good example – a focused learning environment centered around a particular segment. You’re able to build a very dependable program to transfer valuable knowledge that directly translates to a job. As the model is further perfected, it can be then scaled through the web. This type of educational facility is geared towards the longer term, full time student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is a short term skills based education. Skills training. Udemy is a good example – it’s a marketplace that allows anyone to create and distribute online courses that users pay for. The open marketplace lets instructors to create courses where value can be immediately realized so people can buy it, learn, and then recommend. Very different from content that originated from an institution – it’s real people teaching things that work. If we look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/blog/top-ten-earners-on-udemy/&quot;&gt;top 10 instructors on Udemy&lt;/a&gt;, we can see this with courses like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/excel-tutorial/&quot;&gt;Excel for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/how-to-create-awesome-demo-videos/&quot;&gt;How to Create a Demo Video for Your Business&lt;/a&gt;, (I ignored dev courses). This is geared for the hobbyist learner, taking classes on the side trying to pick up a new skill or job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, all are exciting – and I believe that these companies are pushing us towards a shift in education. Education as we have it today is clearly substandard – it’s largely considered an insurance policy – get an education, and you’ll then get a job afterwards. Yet that’s not really the outcome that we’re seeing. We need these new companies to rethink education so we can better match what is needed in the workforce with what is taught in school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration 3.0</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/01/collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/10/01/collaboration</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took part in an online panel on collaboration, organized by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexschiff&quot;&gt;Alex Schiff&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fetchnotes.com/&quot;&gt;Fetchnotes&lt;/a&gt;. Was a fun experience, getting out my own thoughts and hearing from people in other companies like Asana, Yammer, Quip, Wunderlist, Any.do, Do, etc say on the topic. Full post is below, just click on the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@alexschiff/7010281f1426&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/collaboration.png&quot; alt=&quot;collaboration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original response was too long for the panel, so thought I’d paste it here. Some of the points &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/13/Mobile-First-in-the-Enterprise/&quot;&gt;I’ve brought up before&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/10/internet-of-things/&quot;&gt;different posts&lt;/a&gt;, but here it is in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about collaboration tools, there are 3 things that really come to mind - mobile, distributed working, and the internet of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When talking about short term trends in collaboration, mobile is top of mind. It’s not so much an upcoming trend, but something that is already happening. I recently wrote a post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/13/Mobile-First-in-the-Enterprise/&quot;&gt;Mobile First in the Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, that talks about this. As traditional desktop software went online, we got a taste of working outside of the office. Now with mobile, we’re pushing that even further and we’re demanding high quality tools so we can do our jobs anywhere &amp;amp; anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile is a unique form factor in that screen real estate is small, there are built in sensors not available via a browser, and simplicity/single function are dominant. Collaboration reimagined from a mobile first perspective will yield very different tools and experiences than we’re familiar with. Prescient companies are taking this very seriously, and a quick look at popular collaboration tools all treat high quality stand alone mobile apps as a base requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed Working&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related point is distributed working. As mentioned above, modern tools allow us to do quality work outside of the office. We’re pushing this further than we have before with distributed or remote working. As commonly said, there is more talent outside of your locale than in it. And although companies have been adopting this mentality, the tools for distributed working still feel second rate. Lots of these tools help remote teams contribute and communicate, but they feel like individualized solutions under a bigger problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better ways of sharing knowledge, documents, code, etc are certainly important, but another aspect that has been largely ignored is the culture and team building around remote workers. The available tools don’t facilitate and capture the same effect as in person work - the camaraderie, teamwork, excitement, visibility, and other culture building things. These are still largely solved from in person visits and spending time with each other. I’m looking forward to tools and solutions that are built for distributed teams first, and not tools to just help remote teams better contribute to those working in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connected Devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last trend that I think is really important is the Internet of Things. I’m a bit a averse to that phrase as it’s been a bit overused, but I am genuinely excited for the notion of ‘devices talking to devices’. While software has greatly improved in general, what has not dramatically improved is how we interact with software - input has and continues to be manual. We still have to manually type details into Salesforce, type your receipts into a system to create expense reports, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of smartphones coupled with the declining cost of sensors, we’re getting a taste of what life is like with sensors embedded everywhere, capturing and inputting data in for us. A small example of this is something I noticed in Taiwan - inbound buses auto send notifications about arrival time to those in the proximity of the bus stop. That’s a small example of what can be done when devices talk to other devices, and if we think about this and apply it in a workplace setting, amazing solutions can then be created – ie auto logging details of a call into Salesforce, context sensitive time tracking tools, automatically creating/prioritizing/closing tasks on a todo list, and lots of other things that I haven’t even thought of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Hire For Startup</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/27/how-to-hire-for-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/27/how-to-hire-for-startup</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hiring at startups is hard. Startups are a small group of people trying to be super productive and get a lot of shit done. You’re low on money, low on time, and the people you need are getting wooed by other startups or large companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you have to be efficient in finding good people. Recruiting is a huge time suck, but hiring the wrong people &amp;amp; firing is a much more costly exercise, so you have to do your best to be precise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is good and how do you find out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest way I’ve found to explain this is – good people are intellectual curious, focused on results, and always striving for excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things are hard to find in a short inteview. These 3 questions do a decent job &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me your story&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Give me the 1 thing you suck at&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Explain something to me that you care about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the stuff I hear in startup interviews don’t matter. Domain experience is nice, technical trivia can be necessary, but all that really matters is somebody has the right instincts, knows how to learn, and takes ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell me your story. This helps you learn someone’s journey and their decisions over the long term. What you want is an understanding of someone’s innate intellectual curiosity and how those translate into actions and results. People who are curious about things will pursue them, and those will manifest themselves classes they took, side projects, career choices, and mostly importantly, success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question is about striving for excellence. It’s similar to the strengths &amp;amp; weaknesses question, but is more focused – I want to know about the one thing that you think you’re not good at, why you think you’re not good at it, and what are you doing to fix it. Shows focus, introspection, intellectual honestly, and the drive to become better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, explain something to me, shamelessly stolen from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/parand&quot;&gt;Parand&lt;/a&gt;. The question makes a lot of people uncomfortable, but gives you so much information about somebody. Who they are as a person (it’s usually something personal), what they’re passionate about, but most important – you get an understanding of how someone communicates and thinks. I won’t provide too much more detail here, but try this next time and would leave to hear what you take away from this in the commments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about you? Any other great questions or things you look for? Would love to hear in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiiny</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/21/tiiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/21/tiiny</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tiiny.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tiiny&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tiiny.com/&quot;&gt;Tiiny&lt;/a&gt; recently came out from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.n-o-r-t-h-t-e-c-h-n-o-l-o-g-i-e-s.com/&quot;&gt;North&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinrose&quot;&gt;Kevin Rose’s&lt;/a&gt; new &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/17/startup-studio/&quot;&gt;startup studio&lt;/a&gt;. I’m usually pretty cynical when it comes to these types of consumer apps, but I really liked it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is very simple – you can easily share and consume images / looping videos that disappear in 24 hours. It plugs into Twitter, and is displayed in a grid layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good things – the product is beautiful &amp;amp; simple. It’s easy to use, you get it right away and the product is well done. Also plugging into Twitter to seed the platform with content was a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is really light and friendly. Because it’s a mix of images and looping videos, the app comes to life when you open it up. In addition, the grid itself is fantastic, providing a lot of content at once so you can feel like you’re diving into a new world instead of a constrained 1-1 experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really great part is the combination of the grid and the 24 hour photo limit. It gives you a feel and a sense of impermanence and playfulness. The images and looping videos light the grid up, and the 24 hour limit and small images in the grid makes it feel safe and fun to contribute silly stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did feel weird about was connecting this all to Twitter. While I get that it seeds the network faster, it feels weird to plug into a public network given the feeling of intimacy I get from teh app. Would like to really see this applied to an address book with a close knit of friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, thought it was a fun and well done app. We’ll see how it fares longer term :).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Studio</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/17/startup-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/17/startup-studio</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The startup studio. Every entrepreneur I know dreams about building a startup studio, myself included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A startup studio is simply an umbrella organization grouping together a set of ideas &amp;amp; products. What’s great about the studio model is that you’re not tied to any 1 thing like a company is. You’re not constrained to any particular sector, idea, product, etc. – you’re starting with nothing but some general hypotheses, and you can go in any direction you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s awesome about this is the experimental nature of the startup studio. You can explore a variety of ideas at once that can be unrelated or even conflicting – and quickly start/kill any of them at any time. You’re free to think, explore, and learn much faster than you would ordinarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups are hard and scary. In many cases, the end result of a startup has very little to do with the original idea. So the studio model lets you explore and experiement. If you have some inclination, you build &amp;amp; test it. If something isn’t working, you put it to rest and take your lessons. And if something works, you can spin it out and push it further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I love about this is the freedom to practice and exercise the 0 → 1 muscle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blakemasters.com/post/20400301508/cs183class1&quot;&gt;As Peter Thiel has noted&lt;/a&gt;, 0 → 1 is the most difficult stage of building companies, but also the most fun and exciting. And I would love to spend my time focused on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The retort that I hear from people is about a seeming lack of results &amp;amp; focus. If we look at the existing ones – &lt;a href=&quot;http://betaworks.com/&quot;&gt;Betaworks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://expa.com/&quot;&gt;Expa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/obvious&quot;&gt;Obvious&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.n-o-r-t-h-t-e-c-h-n-o-l-o-g-i-e-s.com/&quot;&gt;North&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hvflabs.com/&quot;&gt;HVF&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rocket-internet.com/&quot;&gt;Rocket Internet&lt;/a&gt; – there is a consistnent thesis behind every studio. And some great companies have already been built from these groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s fairly early still in the lifetime of these studios, so we’ll see in a few years how they fair. But the results so far look good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full list of startup studios, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rocket-internet.com/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stefanobernardi&quot;&gt;Stefano Bernardi&lt;/a&gt; for compiling and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/12/apple-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/12/apple-watch</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple-watch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;apple-watch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple watch was just announced a few days ago. Some reviews good, some bad. Regardless, it’s Apple, so the watch will sell. That being said, it is a V1 and there’s a lot of work left for them to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product itself looked good. The software looked nice and the watch as a fitness tracker is the obvious but really great use case. The interchangeable bands are also a nice addition. The interface felt a bit strange though – not sure if tons of tiny icons on a home screen works well. And while I personally don’t like the dial, it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing that felt a bit weird to me was the presentation &amp;amp; the video. It showed Apple Watch doing everything. Texting, heartbeat, movies, calls, showing thousands of pictures, etc. All on this tiny device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that it’s a V1 and still an emerging product category, the use cases are not clearly defined yet. The leading question from everyone was – why do I need one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the Apple Watch (or any smart watch) is an extension of the device in your pocket – not standalone. It is a complement and should enhance some use cases, but not all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning - it can’t do everything a smartphone can. And it shouldn’t have to. The watch should be framed as a complement and an enhancement. Therefore the specific use cases should be well defined and displayed as such. They should show what it can do really well, and not just show all of the things that it can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I do think that Apple will nail down those use cases and work it through. The device will get thinner, the use cases will become more defined, and the product will improve. So I’m absolutely long Apple Watch, just wanted to see better defined use cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/10/internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/10/internet-of-things</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/iot.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology is about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/according-to-pmarca/how-new-technologies-enhance-human-capabilities-a4de8e4beeac&quot;&gt;giving human beings superpowers&lt;/a&gt;. Early computers were tools that helped people perform basic tasks faster and also remember large sets of data. They were awesome for basic processing, storage and retrieval – but those abilities were tied to a local machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the internet. Storage &amp;amp; retrieval coupled with the distribution of the internet gave us incredible reach and access. We could easily share, distribute and retrieve group knowledge - making us smarter, more connected, etc. But we were still tethered to a computer for this - until mobile. Now everyone has all of this magic in their pocket with them everywhere they go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software &amp;amp; technology has continually gotten better over the years and we can now easily store, share &amp;amp; access data anywhere, anytime. But what hasn’t materially changed much is the way we collect and input data. Most data is still collected by a person typing things in via a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPhone gave us a taste of what life would be like with sensors embedded in our lives - collecting data and doing the input for us (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/socialtech/20-hot-locationbased-apps-and-services-you-should-know-about-12841489&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/the-best-apps-that-use-your-phones-boring-features-in-710672640&quot;&gt;accelerometer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.com/article/2455474/open-sesame-how-ios-8-will-unlock-touch-ids-power.html&quot;&gt;fingerprint&lt;/a&gt;). We’re already seeing companies today leveraging these sensors top build awesome products like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nest.com/&quot;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fitbit.com/&quot;&gt;Fitbit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://estimote.com/&quot;&gt;Estimote&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the cost of sensors continues to go down, they will continue to permeate everyday life. &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisyin.com/2014/03/12/taiwan-workcation/&quot;&gt;In another post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that in Taiwan as the bus gets close to the stop, it sends push notifications to users that are in the vicinity. That’s awesome, and just a tiny example of what is possible here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m really excited for everything around us to be connected &amp;amp; help us to collect data and transmit it. The benefits will be enormous, and we will see tons of revolutionary technologies that automate and improve our lives over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare &amp; Swarm</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/05/new-foursquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/05/new-foursquare</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/foursquare-swarm.png&quot; alt=&quot;foursquare-swarm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently Foursquare &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.foursquare.com/post/87012827988/more-on-swarm-and-the-future-of-foursquare&quot;&gt;announced the split&lt;/a&gt; of their service into 2 different apps, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foursquare/id306934924?mt=8&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/US/app/id870161082?mt=8&quot;&gt;Swarm&lt;/a&gt;. The move was to separate the feature they’re largely known for, check-in’s (Swarm), from their new focus, reviews &amp;amp; recommendations (Foursquare).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move doesn’t come as a surprise, but the launch has been less than spectacular. People have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@dweekly/dear-foursquare-c7c441fdf25e&quot;&gt;pretty vocal&lt;/a&gt; about their distaste for the service, and downloads are rankings are both down. There’s even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/killswarmapp&quot;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://killswarmapp.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to killing their new app, Swarm. And the press is &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2014/08/29/as-relaunch-hype-subsides-will-foursquare-survive/&quot;&gt;questioning their ability to survive&lt;/a&gt;. Not looking great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is risk, I wouldn’t count Foursquare out yet. Dennis has always said the vision is local search and they’re just starting to execute on that now. Over the years they’ve just been collecting the data to power this engine. And if you look at the ratings &amp;amp; reviews, the anger is primarily around the product changes as opposed to a commentary on the service. Those that have used the product for what it’s designed for have had decent things to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the above, a common thread that is brought up is Yelp. Those who say Yelp has already won the local restaurant game aren’t seeing what Foursquare could be. Yelp is in the same space, but the focus &amp;amp; products are different. Yelp is a directory, similar to the yellow pages. Foursquare is a recommendation engine that delivers tips based on your tastes. While Yelp has features that mimic Foursquare’s, the products are inherently different. Not a zero sum game, and they can co-exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being said, I do think there is a fair amount of execution risk here. Public perception of Foursquare is not great right now. Plus they’ve raised quite a bit of money &amp;amp; have been around for awhile; their investors may be needing that cash back soon, forcing their hand before it’s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think the real risk is with the product. With their new model of separating check in’s and reviews, they have to more actively craft both sides of this marketplace to keep check-in data coming. Plus they have to make sure people don’t reject the apps post split. Making sure people continue checking in is just as important as people using their reviews serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking from the outside, I’m not sure I agree with the split. I do believe in unbundling &amp;amp; single purpose apps on mobile, but I think in this case I think they should have kept the products together. Checking in and getting reviews are 2 separate functions, but they’re tied together by location. A user shouldn’t have to think about which app to open when they get somewhere – Foursquare should just aim to be the first app users remember to open when they go anywhere. So they risk the user loss from that split, and also risk neglecting one side for the other, causing more loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is all coming from the outside. I have no insight outside of my own speculation, so I could be totally off. Regardless, while there is risk I still think Dennis &amp;amp; team have a lot going for them and I’m still rooting for Foursquare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Valuable Advice</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/02/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/09/02/advice</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Suster recently wrote an article called ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2014/08/30/here-is-how-to-make-sense-of-conflicting-startup-advice/&quot;&gt;How to make sense of conflicting startup advice&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always seeking advice, whether it’s through blogs, podcasts, asking people, etc – and over the years I’ve developed my own framework for getting value out of advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mark’s points are absolutely correct, I’m going to try and simplify and apply it more broadly – how do you get value out of any advice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of how to understand advice is 2 things – to know where you are &amp;amp; what you want, and also to know where the opposing party is &amp;amp; what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Where You Are &amp;amp; What You Want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frequently people that are asking for advice don’t have any idea of what they want. What they are asking for is to get persuaded in some direction or to hear an echo of their own thoughts. This is a flawed way to begin seeking advice. If you don’t know what you want, no amount on advice will get you there. Know the end destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second is to know where you currently stand. That means understanding your skills, perception, network, strengths, weaknesses, etc. Someone who is coming out of MIT is starting from a very different place than someone who is coming out of culinary school. If you don’t know where you currently are and what resources you have, you can’t chart out a clear path to your end goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Where They Are &amp;amp; Where They Want To Go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you need more guidance, you ask people. There are endless quantities of advice out there, and it can be tough to navigate. For every argument in one direction, there’s an equally convincing argument in the other. Blindly asking everyone for advice isn’t going to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s important is to make sure that you seek out the advice that is most relevant to you. Identify people who have not only gone where you’d like to go, but also started from a similar spot. People are prisoners of their own perspective, and they often give advice to themselves instead of doling out tailored advice based on your context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liken this to charting out a course on a map. To get somewhere, you need to know where you want to go. To get there, you need to draw a line from where you currently are to the end goal. If you need to ask for advice, you ask others who have gone to the same place from a similar starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that you should only take advice from people who are exactly the same. Ask a bunch of people for advice, but remember to temper their advice with their context. In many cases the advice itself isn’t important, but it is valuable to understand the framework in which people make decisions. You can then learn from that and improve your own decision making framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coolest Cooler</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/30/coolest-cooler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/30/coolest-cooler</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/coolest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;coolest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ryangrepper/coolest-cooler-21st-century-cooler-thats-actually&quot;&gt;Coolest Cooler&lt;/a&gt; overtook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/597507018/pebble-e-paper-watch-for-iphone-and-android&quot;&gt;Pebble&lt;/a&gt; for most funded Kickstarter campaign ever. The product is really just a fancy cooler with speakers, blenders, bottle opener, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/15/the-5-million-cooler/&quot;&gt;this TechCrunch story&lt;/a&gt;, the first comment pointed out that the real story was not about the $13M raise, but that the founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/profile/ryangrepper&quot;&gt;Ryan Grepper&lt;/a&gt;, had run &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ryangrepper/the-coolest-cooler-with-blender-music-and-so-much/&quot;&gt;almost the exact same campaign with the same product&lt;/a&gt; just under a year ago and failed to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s awesome about this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ryangrepper/the-coolest-cooler-with-blender-music-and-so-much/&quot;&gt;if you look&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ryangrepper/coolest-cooler-21st-century-cooler-thats-actually&quot;&gt;both Kickstarter pages&lt;/a&gt;, the product did not substantial change from one campaign to the other (I’m not sure it changed at all). Some of the details on the Kickstarter page are different, but everything is pretty similar. The only difference is the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what was different the 2nd time around, but what we can take from this is that perseverance through failure is what matters. Ryan obviously believed he had a winner on his hands, and he kept hustling through his 1st failure to pull together a massive success the 2nd time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love reading about this kind of stuff, and so congrats to Ryan and his team for pulling it off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Related Posts</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/23/jekyll-related-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/23/jekyll-related-posts</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spent some time this weekend trying to implement ‘Related Posts’ onto my blog. Wasn’t hard, but also wasn’t as straight forward as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/configuration/&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; is pretty light and wasn’t really helpful for related posts. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;http://charliepark.org/tags-in-jekyll/&quot;&gt;general sentiment&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://techtinkering.com/2011/08/17/improving-related-posts-on-jekyll/&quot;&gt;on the internet&lt;/a&gt; is that Jekyll’s existing related posts function is subpar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most signs point to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LawrenceWoodman/related_posts-jekyll_plugin&quot;&gt;Lawrence Woodman’s library&lt;/a&gt; for overwriting Jekyll’s existing related posts function and replacing it with a better one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s not bad, I prefer using tags instead of categories. Thankfully I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidlynch.org/blog/2011/10/jekyll/&quot;&gt;David Lynch’s blog&lt;/a&gt; and he had an improved version of Lawrence Woodman’s library to do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a file to the &lt;code&gt;_plugins&lt;/code&gt; directory called &lt;code&gt;related_posts.rb&lt;/code&gt; and paste in the code below. Thanks David!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
require 'jekyll/post'

module BetterRelatedPosts

  # Used to remove #related_posts so that it can be overridden
  def self.included(klass)
    klass.class_eval do
      remove_method :related_posts
    end
  end

  # Calculate related posts.
  #
  # Returns [&amp;lt;Post&amp;gt;]
  def related_posts(posts)
    return [] unless posts.size &amp;gt; 1
    highest_freq = Jekyll::Post.tag_freq(posts).values.max
    related_scores = Hash.new(0)
    posts.each do |post|
      post.tags.each do |tag|
        if self.tags.include?(tag) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; post != self
          cat_freq = Jekyll::Post.tag_freq(posts)[tag]
          related_scores[post] += (1+highest_freq-cat_freq)
        end
      end
    end

    Jekyll::Post.sort_related_posts(related_scores)
  end

  module ClassMethods
    # Calculate the frequency of each tag.
    #
    # Returns {tag =&amp;gt; freq, tag =&amp;gt; freq, ...}
    def tag_freq(posts)
      return @tag_freq if @tag_freq
      @tag_freq = Hash.new(0)
      posts.each do |post|
        post.tags.each {|tag| @tag_freq[tag] += 1}
      end
      @tag_freq
    end

    # Sort the related posts in order of their score and date
    # and return just the posts
    def sort_related_posts(related_scores)
      related_scores.sort do |a,b|
        if a[1] &amp;lt; b[1]
          1
        elsif a[1] &amp;gt; b[1]
          -1
        else
          b[0].date &amp;lt;=&amp;gt; a[0].date
        end
      end.collect {|post,freq| post}
    end
  end

end

module Jekyll
  class Post
    include BetterRelatedPosts
    extend BetterRelatedPosts::ClassMethods
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use tags in your front matter, ie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
---
title: Jekyll Related Posts
layout: post
tags:
 - jekyll
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And use this in one of your layouts file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;

  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2014/11/01/youtube-jekyll/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Youtube Videos in Jekyll&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2014/03/30/hosting-a-static-site-on-s3/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Hosting a Static Site on S3&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2014/03/15/subl/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;subl&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Viable Product</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/18/mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/18/mvp</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/spotify-mvp.png&quot; alt=&quot;spotify-mvp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/01/Startup-Assumptions/&quot;&gt;another post I wrote&lt;/a&gt;, the first step that’s important in starting up is thinking through and understanding your assumptions. After you have that, the next step is to then go figure out a way to validate those. Here comes your MVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we get to this part of the conversation, the next thing I hear is a lot of ‘Now I have to build an app to do X’. There are very few cases where you actually need to build something to prove out an idea. If your MVP involves building something from scratch, you likely don’t understand your assumptions enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any product, an MVP is a solution to a problem – a person interacts with a product, and the product does something back for them. The purpose is to quickly test and validate your assumptions – do people have this problem and if so, does my solution actually solve their need? ie – does someone care enough check out my product, and if they do, do they use it again and/or pay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MVP is to validate that statement. Whether the solution is the result of a manual effort or done by a machine likely doesn’t matter to the end user. The user only cares about the end result – does this solve my problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building an app or some sort of product is simply automating a solution so it can scale. But you only want to invest time building and automating after your solution has been validated. Prior to proving this out, focus on the shortest path to validating your assumptions – and there are likely enough free tools out there for you to validate without building anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few examples – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.producthunt.com/&quot;&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt;. It stated out with a basic idea – products are interesting &amp;amp; people care about them. So Ryan &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanhoover.me/post/69599262875/the-wisdom-of-the-20-minute-startup&quot;&gt;started out with a newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, curating products and sending emails out to friends – the core thesis there is that people not only care about products, but also he can curate and present interesting ones. After they newsletter took off, Ryan then recruits friends to then build the site. In the consumer world, people express interest and vote with their time &amp;amp; engagement. Validation –&amp;gt; Product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uncover.com/&quot;&gt;Uncover&lt;/a&gt; has a similar story, but for business. Their idea is that a big part of retainingn talent is rewarding people - so they build a product to reward employees with cool perks. &lt;a href=&quot;http://spencerfry.com/do-things-that-don-t-scale-an-uncover-example&quot;&gt;In the beginning, they manually enabled perks&lt;/a&gt; until they really got some wind behind it and then they automated. In business, people vote with dollars. Validate –&amp;gt; Product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for technical founders, this is the right way to validate an idea. Embark on the shortest path to validate your solution - whether it’s via a manual process or getting a check pre-product. A mockup is worth a million debates &amp;amp; small, manual validations are better than large unvalidated products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest In People, Not Ideas</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/15/adi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/15/adi</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ada.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ada&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college I started an entrepreneurs group with a set of friends. The intent was to get some people together that were interested in building things and boost UCSD’s startup spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point we went to a UCSD demo day. And while there were some fantastic projects there, what stood out to me was a guy that I met there. The guy’s name was Kevin, a 1st year at UCSD out of SF. He told me a little bit about his background – back in high school he had run a fairly successful business selling exotic aqua-life/aquariums out of his garage and was there just to soak in UCSD’s entrepreneurs’ scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately reached out to him afterwards and we met up to spend some time chatting about ideas and what he wanted to do. At the time, he was interested in starting up a services business setting up high-end aquariums (pictured above. Aside – those run from $10-$50k a piece + regular maintenance fees).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I knew absolutely nothing about this business, what I loved was his energy and his authenticity. He’s incredibly knowledgeable about the space and a longtime fish/shrimp enthusiast – in high school he started a blog about his work. The blog ended up being getting a ton of visitors and he built up quite an audience that then became his customers. In addition, he had a ton of credibility, having set up extensive aquariums for high net worth individuals and some large institutions. He put that all on pause to go to college, but after a few months he couldn’t sit still and was tinkering around with a few ideas again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was impressed. His passion was contagious – you could tell this was the only thing he ever wanted to work on. He genuinely loved the space and was constantly expanding the breadth and depth of his knowledge. On the other end, his ability to execute was equally impressive – he worked incredibly hard, had a ‘get shit done’ attitude, and had the right mix of naivete and stubbornness – he was never daunted and would push through regardless of any challenges that arose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we talked, he decided to go forward and start doing side projects again. And what started out as an idea to do high-end installations eventually morphed into &lt;a href=&quot;http://aquadesigninnovations.com/shop/all/&quot;&gt;an ecommerce site&lt;/a&gt; for selling exotic fish out of his apartment. It was a high margin business that was going well, but the logistics were draining – especially for his team of 2 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/adi-store.png&quot; alt=&quot;adi-store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to shift focus onto products. He designed a series of aquaponic systems, recruited materials engineers, prototyped numerous ideas with 3D printers, and then hustled to run &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/kevinzl/ecoqube-desktop-ecosystem-that-grow-flowers-and-he&quot;&gt;a very successful Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; netting him ~$80k and just under 600 orders. He took that to China to find manufactures, build, package, and distribute his product. While he was doing this, he got the attention of Petco, and has found a partner &amp;amp; a fantastic distribution channel for his current and upcoming products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ecoqube.png&quot; alt=&quot;ecoqube&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve had the opportunity to watch Kevin grow tremendously. He’s an incredible entrepreneur with a great sense of product and such a deep knowledge of his space. He’s been working his ass and is on his way to building a great business, recently closing his first round of real funding. It has been fantastic getting the chance to work with him, and I’m excited to be joining his board and continue helping him become successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve learned from all of this is to always invest in the people, not ideas. When vetting the people, remember that authenticity is the most important attribute – in ADI’s case, while the idea has shifted, the passion for the space has never changed. The dedication and resilience to multiple years of pivoting is really hard to fake. In addition, being a hustler coupled with naivete and stubbornness (naive enough to not be daunted by challenges, stubborn enough to push through anyway) make for incredible entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First in the Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/13/Mobile-First-in-the-Enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/13/Mobile-First-in-the-Enterprise</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/star-trek-phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;star-trek-phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in enterprise software. The product that our company builds is a web app and we have mobile apps that act as an extension of our web app. It seems obvious coming from consumer internet, but I still see RFP’s that ask if we sell SaaS or on premise software. That’s the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enterprise moves slowly. It took a long time for companies to come around to actually using the web in the workplace (and still not everyone has yet). That being said, we’ve largely passed the era where you had to prove to buyers that cloud was a superior delivery model than on premise. That is taken almost as fact now and with companies like Workday, Salesforce, Netsuite, etc. now commonplace in the enterprise, those concerns have mostly been negated. Now the transition to the web is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there’s another trend that is going to shape the next wave of enterprise software companies – mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the enterprise shifts from desktop to the web, the same will inevitably happen from web to mobile. With mobile harnessing the same benefits of the web with the added benefit of being always accessible, always connected and easy to use, the enterprise will inevitably make the shift to a predominantly mobile workforce. This is reinforced with the fact that enterprise mobile activations continually go up every quarter as well as the recent Apple / IBM deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’ve floated this around, people always retort with – ‘Enterprise software is complex and difficult to use. How is that going to work on a tiny device?’ A totally valid question, and capturing RFP ready functionality on a mobile device is not easy. But the shift towards mobile in the enterprise is certainly happening, and whether it’s a shift towards mobile as a complement to SaaS based enterprise software or a replacement is a separate point. It’s happening, and the next set of great enterprise companies will not have the luxury of treating mobile as an afterthought or nice to have – it will be a requirement and they will have to think mobile first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that context, I’ve been thinking about enterprise mobile with regard to unbundling / bundling (&lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2014/8/1/app-unbundling-search-and-discovery&quot;&gt;Ben Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.hbr.org/2014/06/how-to-succeed-in-business-by-bundling-and-unbundling/&quot;&gt;Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt;). My understanding of unbundling / bundling is as simple this – things are built to solve problems with today’s technologies. As advancements are made, one can rethink how the same problems can be solved with newer technology. As the new and better solutions are built, they usually ends up looking drastically different – and starting off just focused on a doing a single piece really well (unbundling). As that reaches &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20070701074943/http://blog.pmarca.com/2007/06/the-pmarca-gu-2.html&quot;&gt;product market fit&lt;/a&gt;, other features and services are added on top (bundling). As another major technology shift happens, the cycle repeats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the theory of bundling/unbundling has certainly proved true in the consumer world (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mobile/messenger&quot;&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swarmapp.com/&quot;&gt;Swarm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://googledrive.blogspot.com/2014/04/docssheetsapps.html&quot;&gt;Google Docs/Sheets/Slides&lt;/a&gt;), I’m interested to see how this will play out and if this even rings true in the enterprise. There has already been some unbundling (Salesforce, Workday, Coupa) from incumbents (Oracle, SAP) – and I believe there will be even further unbundling in the context of mobile. The new applications that come out will be mobile first products focused on actions that take advantage of mobile’s form factor and the built in sensors. Eventually products that do that well will rise to prominence and we’ll see another wave of those bundling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how it plays out, mobile is transfomrative to the enterprise, and I’m interested in seeing how this evolves over time and what innovative companies/products come out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Asana</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/10/asana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/10/asana</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Asana. I live in it and very literally would not know what to do without it. This is a quick rambling on why :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open up the app for the first time, Asana resembles a blank todo list. Once you see it, you already know what to do – create tasks. The application opens with a very familiar UX for the end user. Simplicity and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/asana-blank-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;asana-blank-screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that alone isn’t enough. While a simple todo list is great, there’s nothing different about that than any other task management app – Todoist, Wunderlist, Any.do, Clear, etc. The UX is the same across the board – here’s a blank list, start adding some tasks. Nothing groundbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Todoist.png&quot; alt=&quot;Todoist&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/Wunderlist.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Wunderlist&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/Any.do.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Any.do&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/clear.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Clear&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s great about a todo list is that everybody knows what it is and how to use it. But a todo list alone is not enough. A quick observation into how many people use task management apps shows 2 main behaviors – people either try it and eventually go back to what they’re used to (writing it down, emailing it to yourself, keeping it in your head, evernote), or they fill it up with everything and then never revisit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todo list apps pick up steam quickly because everybody understands the basic principle. But the reason people also burn out on them so quickly is that the present day understanding of a todo list is that it’s for the short term. Tasks for the day, grocery lists, etc. You finish it and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But true task management is more than just short term tasks. A major component of life is managing the long term. But managing a long term todo list is hard. Because of the dynamic nature of long term projects, the long term todo list is constantly changing and shifting – new tasks pop up &amp;amp; old ones go away. Some tasks stay open for a long time and need notes. Some tasks require multiple people, documents, etc. And not all tasks in a long term project are relevant at the same time. So what happens is you create a long term task list, and you’re either recreating it over and over, can’t fit everything in there, or something else. Regardless, the todo list can begin to become a job to maintain instead of empowering you to work more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So todo lists are great for the short term, but not so much for longer term projects. What is great about Asana is that it gets us closer to combining short term and long term into a single application. While everything starts out as a task - as you continue to build on it, you can group them together into a project. You can tag things, create sub projects into tasks, add headers, subtasks, due dates, documents, comments, collaborators, etc. So you start with a simple task list and over time you create projects, and sub projects. Then you can use the due date / timing functionality to only surface what’s important to you when you need it. Storing the long term, but only exposing the short term to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/asana-full-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;asana-full-screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the beauty of Asana is the simplicity. A familiar and intuitive UX, but also with powerful features &amp;amp; workflow built in and hidden to the end user until they need them. Also, a non trivial part of Asana’s success is Luna. Your task manager just has to work and not slow you down, and Asana’s web app is one of the best I have ever used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the other apps above share some of the features geared at managing longer term tasks/projects, they lack in one way or another some or the power user tools that really help bridge the gap from short term to long term task list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Asana is fantastic, there are just a few things that I’d like to see it expand on -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More tools for long term projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Asana’s power user tools help you focus on the short term &amp;amp; plan for the long term, it’s not perfect. Longer term projects are comprised of tasks, but those tasks live independently of each other. A way to improve the ability to manage longer term projects in Asana would be task dependencies - complete task X, task Y is auto assigned to you. Another would be a tool to help you revisit projects. In today’s world where a single person runs multiple concurrent projects, the ability to alert the user that Project X has seen no work in awhile or have Project X resurface after completion of Project Y would be extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priorities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separation between important and not important. This is a tricky one, but the essence is that some tasks are more/less important than others. When you use Asana as a single source of truth, there can be a lot of things in there. What I’m starting to see is task creep. I forward everything into Asana, and so I can easily be overwhelmed by all the things I need to do. It feels like my inbox. What I want to easily pull out of Asana is the 2 things that I really need to do today, and leave everything else as a secondary task until these important ones are done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Anonymity Still Sucks</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/04/Why-Anonymity-Still-Sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/04/Why-Anonymity-Still-Sucks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/23/secret-cyberbullying/&quot;&gt;a lot of talk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bustle.com/articles/34337-bullying-is-a-problem-for-all-of-us-and-the-app-secret-needs-to-do-something&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt; about anonymity. Some, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pando.com/2014/08/03/now-weve-seen-secrets-ugly-soul-will-investors-act/&quot;&gt;like Pando&lt;/a&gt;, are claiming that anonymity is horrific and companies like Secret are not only morally bankrupt, but also enabling online bullying. While that position feels a bit strong to me, I do think there is some truth to what is being said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the web has been an anonymous place. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4chan#Media_attention&quot;&gt;4chan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formspring#Controversies&quot;&gt;Formspring&lt;/a&gt;, Myspace – everything was anonymous. There was no sense of identity on the web and these places ended up being really toxic – known for lies, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/life/bulle/2010/03/how_should_facebook_and_myspace_handle_cyberbullying.html&quot;&gt;bullying&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/9/17/4740902/no-good-answers-why-didnt-ask-fm-learn-from-the-formspring-suicides&quot;&gt;even suicides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Facebook came to exist, and while there were likely sites before Facebook that were centered around real identity on the web, Facebook was the first to really take off. This cemented the idea that we should use our real identities on the web, and the next batch of companies followed suit. The web became a much nicer place. Now that we’re dipping our toes back into anonymity, it’s clear that not much has changed from the earlier days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anonymity is still producing the same result as before because fundamentally people are only as nice as it is convenient for them to be. And behind a mask on the internet, that bar is pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anonymity removes accountability. And without accountability, people say/do bad things. And this is not specific to the internet - this is everywhere. So applying anonymity at scale on the web is likely not a good idea at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say anonymity is all bad. There are certainly positives around anonymity – the obvious ones being an outlet for emotional burdens, stress, relationship issues, etc. Being able to express these feelings safely to others can do a lot of good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there’s definitely value in anonymity. But it has to be done tastefully to mitigate/eliminate the bad sides of anonymity, and it’s clear from the current implementation that we are not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m always a big proponent that you shouldn’t criticize something unless you’ve got a solution. So as I’ve been thinking about how anonymity has been done well in the real world, it has lead me to groups like Alcoholics Anonymous (and other anonymous groups).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My impression on why these groups work well is 2 things – alignment of interests and small community. A smaller community feels like a decent way to maintain some sort of accountability in an anonymous setting. And the singular focus around a specific topic aligns the group, making it easier to self police when people stray off topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think in our first iteration around anonymity 2.0, we should start with similar principles – group focus around a singular topic as well as some method of accountability (not sure if limiting a group by size works here, may actually lead to more bullying, but putting place some mechanism to prevent it from being totally open).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unvalidated Assumptions</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/01/Startup-Assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/08/01/Startup-Assumptions</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find myself explaining this more and more often as friends of mine talk about ideas that they are considering/pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conversations inevitably lead to talk about some sort of product. More often than not, what I hear for their version of an MVP is is far too large, focused on the wrong things (features, UI), and most importantly – built on unvalidated assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When thinking through ideas, the initial focus should not be product. The focus should be on the problem. Understand the problem deeply and boil it down to its basic principles. What’s the core issue, who does it affect, how acute the pain is, what are the current solutions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing during this exercise is not just to understand the problem – but to also get a deep understanding of your assumptions. Excited founders &amp;amp; startup people tend to speak in absolutes when talking about problems. ie - People can’t find good restaurants to eat, people hate using their CRM, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baked into these problem statements are always several unvalidated assumptions. In the restaurant example above - while it may be true, the assumption is that people actually care enough to do something about it. That may or may not be true – and if true, is that group of people large enough to justify building a service for? And even further – in that set of people, who is actually willing to pay for a solution (or is that set large enough to serve ads to)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building on top of unvalidated assumptions is risky – it’s easy to spend lots of time building something that nobody wants or can’t stand on its own two feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So make sure that before you start talking about a product or an MVP to qualify your problem statement, understand your assumptions, and then go out to validate those assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Apps</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/28/Scheduling-Apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/28/Scheduling-Apps</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been seeing more and more ‘personal assistant’ scheduling products coming out, touting the ability to relieve you of wasted time scheduling meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ostensibly these products were built and designed to make money at some point. As a consumer, I use calendaring infrequently – occasional get togethers, errands, etc. Not enough to spend money on a service. The bulk of calendar pain is work related – so these products must be targeted at a business audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that’s true, the apps today are missing the mark. The majority of the apps I’ve tried function the same way – cc an alias and they’ll help you schedule a meeting. What they don’t mention is that they’re really optimized for basic meetings (1:1, immediate scheduling, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pain is not around basic meetings – it’s around the complex ones. Coordinating between multiple people. Multiple time zones. Adding a conference call dial in to every meeting. Then cancelling and rescheduling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These products fail under the strain of complex meetings. Either a delay in response (invites never show up) or just silently failing. That type of slip or delay at work can be extremely costly. There is little room &amp;amp; patience for error – and when ~85% of meetings are complex, the supposed benefits of the product are quickly overshadowed by its shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I realize that many of these products are early stage and MVP’s. However - either they didn’t fully understand the problem or their MVP is coming up short. An MVP is the shortest &amp;amp; quickest path to prove out a solution. These products have proved the existence of a problem, but not a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my eyes, an MVP for this type of product is at a minimum - multiple person scheduling, possibly automated conf call dial ins in the invite. A V2 (possibly a paid version, leaving the base product free) is the ability to configure personal preferences. ie for me – no calls on Tuesdays, prefer to take them from 2-6pm PT. Another element is factoring in meeting priority and rescheduling and reprioritizing based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m confident we’ll get there eventually, the early incarnations of the software’s shortcomings and frustrations are far greater than value add.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Teams</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/26/Hot-Teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/26/Hot-Teams</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9JOibQNHyF0&quot;&gt;PandoMonthly’s Mike Maples&lt;/a&gt; interview the other day, and he mentioned a concept called ‘Hot Teams’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hot team is defined as a team that is exponentially more productive than other teams. This is the essence of good startups, and was thinking about this concept - ie what makes up a hot team?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designthinkingblog.com/http:/www.designthinkingblog.com/tom-kelley-on-ideo-and-effective-innovation/#sthash.J3cmukih.dpuf&quot;&gt;a bit of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basadur.com/insightsresearch/OurThoughtsonCreativityandInnovation/HowDoYouCreateaHotTeam/tabid/115/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;reading around&lt;/a&gt;, I came to this -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hot team is a group that is defined by the following characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s a vision that people believe in.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nobody is above any job.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ideas and truth always win.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Any individual can make a difference.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Temporary brokenness is better than permanent paralysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net of this is this to form a team that fits &lt;a href=&quot;http://25iq.com/2014/07/13/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-from-peter-thiel/&quot;&gt;Peter Thiel’s High Alignment / High Trust&lt;/a&gt; matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/hotteamsmatrix.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for those of us that manage teams (especially in a startup), we need remember to always to live by the principles above to win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Figure Out A Competitor's Strategy</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/21/How-To-Figure-Out-A-Competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/21/How-To-Figure-Out-A-Competitor</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When evaluating any opportunity/company/etc, you should always do a competitive analysis. A competitive analysis is an overview of the landscape – what’s the space, who are the players, their strategy, and how are they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is typically done in a few ways – read about the space in an analyst report (or some general market overview), understand the problem/proposed solution, identify competitors, and then read about them. (I’ll write about each piece in a different post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read into competitors, you can run through a few sites to get a good general overview – the company’s Businessweek profile, Crunchbase, AngelList, Wikipedia, etc. To get a more in depth overview, you can read the company’s website, blog, press releases, and product review. Through reading all of this, you can start to get an understanding of the product, the business and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While helpful, the problem is that this type of public information rarely provides anything unique or enlightening. While you can sort of glean a semblance of a strategy from all of this, it can be tough to figure out what is actually going on at the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good way to get deeper insight into a company is reading through the company’s career page. The job posts that a company has out are very revealing into what the company is currently focused on. They’re either hiring to fix a problem (weakness) or they’re hiring to invest in that particular area (strategy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extension of this is read into past hires – management team, leadership, old employees &amp;amp; new employees. If you read into their backgrounds, tenure, people who left and new hires, you can get a deeper sense into the dynamics and pace of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing the people and hiring patterns of a company with press &amp;amp; other company news can give you a deeper understanding and more ammo when trying to understand a company from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Let's Stop Saying B2B</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/09/lets-stop-saying-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/07/09/lets-stop-saying-b2b</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been seeing more people using the word B2B incorrectly. Mostly falsely conflating B2B, SMB and Enterprise (esp in the startup world). They are vastly different, so here’s my attempt to clear it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit of context - I work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/U4ZvG1&quot;&gt;Coupa&lt;/a&gt;, a late stage enterprise software startup. We build and sell software to large companies via subscription model. Before, I was at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/18MuCue&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt;. We built and sold subscription software to businesses of any size, but primarily in the SMB space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are B2B companies. But B2B != enterprise or SMB. Grouping them together or comparing any SMB focused startup to an enterprise focused startup is plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, we were selling software to businesses with 1 goal – making sure that Lifetime value of the customer (how much they paid us over the length of our relationship, LTV) was greater than the cost of customer acquisition (how much it cost us to get &amp;amp; support them, CAC). LTV &amp;gt; CAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, different strategies led us to different places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Xpenser, we embraced freemium – free for individuals &amp;amp; $9/user/month for companies. Users can try for free &amp;amp; setup their own accounts. The goal was to convert users that were business users, and use free users as marketing. Flat fee per month included everything (setup, support, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Coupa, there is no free user plan. There isn’t even a place to sign up. We directly sell (or channel) multi-year contracts to big companies. The pricing varies and we also additionally charge for implementation (setup), integrations, and provide different tiers of support plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freemium at Xpenser attracted SMB’s, and direct sales at Coupa gets us enterprise accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To define SMB vs. Enterprise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Small_and_medium_enterprises&quot;&gt;Small &amp;amp; Medium sized Businesses (SMB’s)&lt;/a&gt; – while defined in many different ways, for the sake of this post, we’ll say that SMB’s are companies with less than 250 employees or $50M in revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise = large companies. Multi hundred millions to billions in revenue &amp;amp; large organizations (often public companies) with lots of people in offices globally. Think biggest companies in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core difference between SMB &amp;amp; Enterprise is their behavior – how they discover, buy &amp;amp; use software. This difference in behavior shapes how you interact with them and how to build your product &amp;amp; your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMB’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SMB’s are more like consumers in the way they discover &amp;amp; purchase software - through news, marketing, referrals and they value price, efficiency &amp;amp; speed. A few points -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They’re cheaper &amp;amp; pay you less.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;They have less requirements.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;They buy and setup faster.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The buyer and user are often the same.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cost of switching is low (not much sunken cost &amp;amp; lots of alternatives).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion, cost of sale &amp;amp; $/customer is low. Cost of support/maintenance is mid-high, cost of switching is low, and churn is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning for LTV &amp;gt; CAC to work, you need lots &amp;amp; lots of customers to sign up &amp;amp; setup by themselves, not leave too quickly, and not bug you for support. The more support, the harder it is for the math to work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprise buyers are very different in how they discover and buy software. Discovery is through analyst reports &amp;amp; direct/channel sales. Lots of decision makers (slow moving) &amp;amp; different incentives (sometimes conflicting with common sense) and they value stability, proven outcomes, &amp;amp; safe decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They’re not as price sensitive. Big checks.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Buying takes a long time. &lt;em&gt;Lots&lt;/em&gt; of people involved.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;They have massive requirements. Not all are logical.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The buyer and user are not often the same (affects churn).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cost of switching is high (lots of sunken cost in buying &amp;amp; setting up).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion is high(-er than free trial converts), $/customer &amp;amp; cost of sale/support/switching are all high, and churn is lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning for LTV &amp;gt; CAC, you need a lot of sales/implementations/support people to land a few massive customers over time and then keep them. Costs a lot up front, but over time the math works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are 2 different customers with entirely different behaviors. And the reason they don’t overlap is the product you build &amp;amp; the distribution strategy for 1 audience has very little overlap with the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For SMB’s, they care about buying a product that solves their business problem. So focusing solely on product works. Discovery &amp;amp; distribution is via marketing &amp;amp; converting signups/free trials. It’s nice – low CAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad news is $/customers is low, churn is high and support can also be high. So hitting a meaningful LTV &amp;gt; CAC requires lots of customers, low touch conversions and little support. With low of cost of switching &amp;amp; high curn in a crowded market like SMB software, that can be tough. Some companies try to jump from SMB to enterprise, but it’s incredibly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Enterprise, the buyer is buying a solution for 1000’s of people. Meaning lots of $ to spend, lots of requirements, and it’s important for them to make the right decision (long decision cycle). For the same formula to work, you need much higher $/customer (ACV) in order to cover the initial high cost of sale (long sales cycle, implementation, support).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solving a business problem is not enough either – you need to meet RFP requirements, which always includes cumbersome things like expensive security compliance, IE7/8 support, and unnecessary features that are reminders of an old broken process. Building an RFP ready product is not always the same as building a good/usable product (user != buyer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So even when operating in the same space, both SMB/Enterprise businesses are entirely different. Customers, discovery, distribution, and product all differ. Even if an SMB manages to attract an enterprise client, they won’t be equipped to handle the enterprise sales cycle. Or their product won’t make it past the RFP. And visa versa – if an enterprise startup tried to attract an SMB client, they would likely be too expensive, move too slowly, or the product would look too far off from what the client is expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So which is better? Neither. There are fantastic companies that have executed on both strategies. But they’re not the same, so let’s stop falsely conflating SMB/Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Selling Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/06/29/Dangers-of-Selling-Roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/06/29/Dangers-of-Selling-Roadmap</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saw this on Twitter a few weeks ago &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://twitter.com/GreggDourgarian'&gt;@GreggDourgarian&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s the difference between selling your product and selling your engineering bandwidth. The latter is your lifeblood.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Sacks (@DavidSacks) &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/DavidSacks/statuses/474400870910554112'&gt;June 5, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone does it. It’s especially tempting to sell roadmap when you’re early in the game and you need the customers/revenue to gain some traction. But at some point you need to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time you sell engineering bandwidth, you incur some debt. The business continues forward, but development lingers behind trying to fulfill the promises. Eventually the delta gets very large, and you’ve got a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s 2 big problems with selling features/roadmap -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/features-iceberg.png&quot; alt=&quot;feature-iceberg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to keep track of. Building features is not just development - there’s lots of hidden costs outside of pure development. Which means the estimates (especially those made during a sales cycle) are frequently incorrect. These backlogged items are very hard to keep track of and can build up very quickly. Before you know it, you can be backlogged for a very long time, derailing your entire product strategy and roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales can develop a habit of relying on this. When sales begins relying on selling promised features instead of product, it’s no longer a value sell. It becomes a feature/function war, and the customer will view you as a commodity instead of valued partner - meaning you’re replaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not easy and it takes discipline as an organization, but in order to build a scaleable business with a solid foundation, you have to rely on selling a solution, and not features of a product. Especially ones that don’t exist yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Commandments For Every Product Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/06/26/10-Rules-For-Every-Product-Manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/06/26/10-Rules-For-Every-Product-Manager</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dilbert-pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;dilbert-pm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a lot of people ask me what a PM is or does. Everyone has their own definition but here’s my take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of the PM is to create scaleable revenue via product. This means always being in sync with both the macro and the micro – from business opportunity, risks, competition – to which features to build, active deals, risk customers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job is to then synthesize all of that information and turn it into a roadmap. And a roadmap isn’t just a list of features to build. It’s a plan on how to build a scaleable and profitable business around a product. This means owning the entire product – development, distribution, and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, the PM needs to not only enable other teams (development, ops, sales, services, support, marketing) in the organization to succeed, but they need to deeply understand how each team functions – what’s working and what’s broken – what to fix now and what can wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, the PM’s job is to take all of blame and none of the credit. It’s to be the leader, the backbone, and the glue of the organization. Anything short of this is failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bit more detail – &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Own The Vision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find it ruthlessly by living in the future, and constantly reassess it against the current state of things. Set aside time regularly to think about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Understand Reality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you need to dream up a grand vision, you also have to keep your eyes on the road at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Vision without execution is hallucination.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Communicate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t achieve greatness alone. There’s always a team involved, and make sure everyone understands where they’re going, how, and why. Dont’ be afraid to constantly repeat yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prioritize Ruthlessly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are endless things you can get pulled in – dev, sales, support, services – but there’s only 24 hours a day – where is your time best spent? Make sure every minute you spend working has the highest impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good way to think about this is – (Value created) / (time spent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Own The Product&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should know the in’s and out’s of your product. Know the short term, long term, any debt you’re building up, quick wins, gamechangers, experiments, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Own Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales/Marketing is not someone else’s problem. It’s yours. Make sure your messaging is right, people can find your product, use it, extract real value, and then tell others about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Own Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless what business you’re in, you need users/customers. In almost all cases, the more the better (for us in SaaS, you live and die by LTV). High churn will kill you just as fast as a lack of sales. Great support keeps your users/customers with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Always Be Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re going to make mistakes. That’s fine. What’s not fine is repeating those mistakes. You must constantly be evaluating the outcome – what worked, what didn’t work and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Don’t Let Competition Distract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your ears open on competitors, but don’t let them affect your plans. This takes a tremendous amount of discipline. Practice it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Always Be Recruiting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resourcing is your problem, not HR’s. If you can’t sell the opportunity to somebody, you’ve got bigger problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this above can seem like a lot to take in, and it’s easy to get overwhelmed. The job of the PM is to understand all of this, prioritize, and balance their time and energy across all of these things. It’s not easy, but ultimately it’s incredibly rewarding. Hopefully that helps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some additional reading about PM from some smart people :) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Product-Management/What-distinguishes-the-Top-1-of-Product-Managers-from-the-Top-10&quot;&gt;How to be a 1% PM - Ian McAllister&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benhorowitz.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/good-product-manager.pdf&quot;&gt;Good PM, Bad PM - Ben Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.adamnash.com/2011/12/16/be-a-great-product-leader/&quot;&gt;Be a Great Product Leader - Adam Nash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/techtalk/archive/2005/12/16/504872.aspx&quot;&gt;PM at Microsoft - Steven Sinofsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sachinrekhi.com/blog/2013/03/18/the-art-of-decision-making-as-a-product-manager&quot;&gt;Art of Decision Making as a PM - Sachin Rekhi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pmarchive.com/guide_to_startups_part4.html&quot;&gt;The Only Thing That Matters - Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Scale With Your Startup</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/05/20/how-to-scale-as-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/05/20/how-to-scale-as-a-leader</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a startup guy (most recently of Xpenser, a 3 person startup), I have the habit of trying to do everything. Figure out the long term, short term, and get to work – regardless of the type of task. It’s a lot of fun – constantly figuring it out, learning new things, and getting stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now at Coupa, we’ve got a much larger team (~200), more customers, and separate functions. &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisyin.com/2013/04/17/hello-coupa/&quot;&gt;When I joined&lt;/a&gt;, I brought with me the same style of work – do anything and everything. Not long after, my calendar was quickly booked nonstop 8-8 every single day, I was sleeping minimal hours, working weekends, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/27/pretending-to-work/&quot;&gt;perpetually behind&lt;/a&gt;. I had to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I realized was that at Xpenser, I was playing the role of (what I call) ‘the hero’ – the one man army. That means being on all sales calls during the day, manning all new visitor chats, answering all support emails/calls and implementing customers. At night, doing designs, marketing, recruiting, and long term planning. And this wasn’t just me – everyone on the team played the same role — we just didn’t have enough resources to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; do everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this works at a small startup, it’s not scaleable and can’t last forever. Being the hero and being involved in every ground level decision inevitably leads to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-04-12/how-to-avoid-burnout-marissa-mayer&quot;&gt;exhaustion, burn out and resentment&lt;/a&gt; as the company/workload grows. Eventually you’ll bottleneck and become a hinderance to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I realized was that as a company is rapidly scaling, ‘the hero’ must to evolve into a leader. That means abstracting yourself from the day to day, and getting the right people around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role of the leader is to focus on the long term and set the attitude &amp;amp; pace to achieve the goal. The number one priority for the leader is to focus on the people — make sure they have the right tools to do their job and and make sure they feel safe to think for themselves and do what they think is right. You have to learn to not jump in when something is going wrong – learn to just guide and trust they’ll figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a startup guy, that’s how to scale with a quickly growing company. It’s been a challenge so far to do this, takes a good amount of self control – I still get an itch to jump in and try and just do it myself. But overall, so far I’m working better, smarter, and feeling healthier as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, I don’t think it’s good to spend all of your time only doing long term work. It can put you out of touch with reality. Knowing the real work is essential, and even taking on small projects yourself once in a while is good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Consumers Won't Pay for Apps</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/05/05/consumer-productivity-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/05/05/consumer-productivity-apps</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People don’t like paying for software. Despite being incredibly cheap relative to how much value it provides, most people still gawk at the idea of paying for a $.99 app (or any software). Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about this after reading Hunter Walk’s recent post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hunterwalk.com/2014/04/24/why-wont-consumers-pay-for-productivity-apps/&quot;&gt;‘Why won’t consumers pay for productivity apps?’&lt;/a&gt;. His point – consumer productivity software might fare better if they exposed metrics about the value they were providing – ie. how much time they saved you, how many emails they sent for you, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shocked to see most commenters either agreeing or pointing to other examples of productivity software that smartly did this. While they weren’t wrong – it probably would be helpful if productivity software promoted their metrics more – they were all missing the point entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that consumers not only don’t care about productivity, they also value money &amp;gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at the average consumer’s behavior, they’re not focused on productivity. Consumers either are either home after a long day at work or they’re hanging out with friends on the weekend. They’re thinking about relaxing, taking it easy, and enjoying themselves. Productivity is not a high priority for the consumer (I wrote about solving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/21/freemium-doesn%27t-always-work-in-b2b/&quot;&gt;the right priorities here&lt;/a&gt;). That’s why you see most successful consumer applications geared towards leisure – Facebook, Instagram, Yelp, etc. Productivity doesn’t fit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the average consumer values money much more than their own time. Since there are no explicit tasks/agenda for them, they value their own time at $0.00. So many things are more valuable than their time (esp. money). So trying to monetize consumer productivity is an uphill battle – also why popular consumer apps are free and ad supported as opposed to subscription based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All productivity software either starts as pure B2B or eventually leans and focuses on the B2B market. Because the product matches the buyers intent, that’s where the money is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a footnote, I’ll say that I do think that as time goes on, we’ll have an increase in the number of consumers that value time &amp;gt; money and are willing to pay for software. But we still have a long way to go, and I’m unsure if this will ever be the predominant consumer mentality – I simply believe that this consumer group is increasing in size.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a Static Site on S3</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/30/hosting-a-static-site-on-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/30/hosting-a-static-site-on-s3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this setup with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisyin.com&quot;&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt; for some time now, but I recently had to setup another static site and I had to look through my old setup and Google around a bit and try to figure out how to do it again. Figured I would write it down this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy A Domain&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Create a Bucket on S3&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Upload Content&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Configure Bucket&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Point Domain to Bucket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy A Domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a ton of places to do this (people seem to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; a lot), but I stick with Godaddy because all my domains are already here, and they keep giving me &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.godaddy.com/deals2/&quot;&gt;$0.99 domains&lt;/a&gt;. Anything works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Bucket on S3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an S3 account, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; and sign up. It’s free for 5 GB storage, 20K Get Requests, 2K Put Requests, and 15GB of data transfer out each month for one year. For most, it will be free but if you think you’ll do more than that, their pricing is &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/s3/pricing/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re in the S3 console, click ‘Create Bucket’ in the top left hand corner. All your files will be stored here. Name your bucket ‘www..com’. For Region, just leave the default ‘US Standard’ and then click ‘Create’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/createbucket.png&quot; alt=&quot;createbucket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your bucket, time to upload. You can do either via UI or command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To upload via UI, click Upload in the top left hand corner and select or drag folders in. Once your files have been uploaded, right click the files and select ‘Make Public’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/makepublic.png&quot; alt=&quot;makepublic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easier and faster way is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://s3tools.org/s3cmd&quot;&gt;s3cmd&lt;/a&gt;, a command line tool for S3. Once you setup and configure s3cmd with your access keys, find your bucket and upload with below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ s3cmd ls # find your bucket in the list
$ s3cmd sync --acl-public folder_name/ s3://www.domain.com

# example for folder '_site' and bucket www.chrisyin.com
$ s3cmd sync --acl-public _site/ s3://www.chrisyin.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure Bucket&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return to the main S3 console and highlight your bucket (but don’t go into it). Select ‘Properties’ in the top right hand corner. The 2 sections we need to configure are ‘Permissions’ and ‘Static Website Hosting’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/bucketproperties.png&quot; alt=&quot;bucketproperties&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Permissions, click ‘Add More Permissions’, select ‘Everyone’ and check ‘View Permissions’. Click Save in the bottom right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/everyonepermissions.png&quot; alt=&quot;everyonepermissions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then open up ‘Static Website Hosting’. In here, select ‘Enable website hosting’, define your index/404 files, and then click Save. There’s also URL next to ‘Endpoint:” - that is the URL for your static site. If you click on it, it should show your the site. If that’s working, now we’ll point your domain to that URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/index404.png&quot; alt=&quot;index404&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Point Domain to Bucket&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go into your domain registrar. Everyone’s steps now are going to be different depending oin your registrar. If you use Godaddy, click on ‘My Account’ –&amp;gt; ‘My Domains’, select your domain and then ‘Launch’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the domain info and next to ‘Settings’, select ‘DNS Zone File’ and then click ‘Edit’ – change CNAME record with Host:www and point it to your Endpoint URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/staticsite/cname.png&quot; alt=&quot;cname&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then click back into the main setting and then for forwarding, set your forwarding to &lt;em&gt;wwww.domain.com&lt;/em&gt;. Done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now both &lt;em&gt;domain.com&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;wwww.domain.com&lt;/em&gt; should work for your site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>subl</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/15/subl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/15/subl</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Opening files via Finder was beginning to be a pain in the ass, so figured I should do it via the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick search online yielded a bunch of results – most did not work for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breaking my bash profile and spending a ton of time going through a bunch of options, eventually found something that did work (below). Thought I’d share to save anyone else the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
cd
vim .bash_profile
# add below to your bash profile
alias subl=&amp;quot;/Applications/Sublime\ Text.app/Contents/SharedSupport/bin/subl&amp;quot;
$ source .bash_profile
$ subl --help
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Workcation</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/12/taiwan-workcation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/03/12/taiwan-workcation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got back from a 2.5 week workcation. I wanted to get out of town &amp;amp; get some new ideas, inspiration, and soak in some culture from outside of the US. Since I have family in Taiwan, it seemed like a pretty easy &amp;amp; low risk choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still had to work, so I decided I’d work PT, but in Taiwan. Taiwan is 16 hours ahead (add 4 hours to PT and switch the AM/PM) – so I work from 12am-9am in Taiwan (8am-5pm PT). Sleep from 11am-6pm, work on side projects until 12am and then back to Coupa work. Weekends were mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taiwan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;taiwan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Taiwan was awesome. The food there is amazing – cheap, fast, delicious, and everywhere. Transportation is fast and readily available. People are really friendly. Altogether, it was really fun &amp;amp; interesting to see the differences between their society and ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of things stood out, but 2 things that really impressed me were the transportation and the self-serve culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transportation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, getting around was really easy – and a better overall experience than anything I’ve dealt with in America. There are cabs &amp;amp; buses everywhere – you can flag a cab anywhere at any time in under a minute. Plus the bus has a free app that will send you a push notification when it’s close. Really nice, the first implementation I’ve seen of ‘objects talking to objects’. Pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taiwan-mrt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mrt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real winner in Taiwanese transportation is the subway system. Cheap, fast, on time, and clean. What’s really amazing is the card. You get a plastic card that you load with money – you tap it against a terminal to get in, and tap again to get out. So much better than swipe or insert ticket – pretty small detail, but made everything just that much easier &amp;amp; faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the really nice thing about this card is the integration of this card with the rest of Taiwan. You can use it at any 7-11/corner store (these are everywhere – often multiple on a single block). It’s also getting integrated into apartments. Meaning your subway card can get you around town, buy food, and open your house door. So awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taipei-mrt-easy-card.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;mrtcard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, getting around in Taiwan is just easy. And you only need a single card to leave the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus – Taiwan also has a bunch of public bike racks around town that you can check out and ride around. It’s free for the first 30 minutes, and there’s a corresponding app that tells you where they are, where you can park, etc. And to check a bike out, you just need to use your subway card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taiwan-bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;taiwanbike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self Serve Culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of transportation, one of the major differences that I noticed between Taiwan and America was an inherent culture of self serve. Everything and everyone seemed to be very self contained and respectful of their surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taipei-fish-market.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fishmarket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you walk into a restaurant, you seat yourself. You don’t get offered water. You grab the menu yourself. If you want to order, you go up and order. This pattern was everywhere – food, shopping, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most prominent thing was how clean everything was. Because space is a constraint, everything is shared. Tables, chairs, personal space. And because of the volume of people, nobody cleans up after you. So everything is shared by lots of people, yet still remain clean. Sharp contrast to shared American public utilities. The biggest surprise to me was the subway – 1000’s of people getting on and off hundreds of times a day, and no litter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/taiwan-clean-mrt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clean-mrt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, my trip was great. My main takeaways – Taiwan seems to be a faster moving country than America in terms of integrating technology into mainstream life. I suspect this is a byproduct of the fact that Taiwan is much smaller; therefore, change is easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing was the respect an awareness of the surrounding environment. People were largely self policing – which was pretty amazing to see at a large scale. In America we sometimes see this behavior in controlled environments, but to see the general population behave this way was cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely going to return, would love to bring some of that back to America :).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment&#58; Movie Annotation</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/02/03/movie-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/02/03/movie-annotation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, have been working on a small side project to help people understand movies/tv shows better. A lot of times after I watch something, I’ll lurk on Wikipedia/IMDB/Reddit etc to find answers to any outstanding questions. Sometimes just I’ll casually float around the web to revisit some of the scenes, discover any subtleties I may have missed, or just talk about how awesome/shitty something was. Some notable times I’ve done this – after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/faq&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prometheus2-movie.com/community/forums/42&quot;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;, and after every &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/breakingbad&quot;&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/a&gt; episode in the second half of Season 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would spend a fair amount of time collecting bits of information from around the web, consolidating it into my mind to form a cohesive story, explain it to a friend, and then I’d be satisfied. But it was a massive time suck and an enormous pain in the ass. To find the info I’d have to scour the web – on one end, going through generic synopses on Wikipedia (usually really high level and poorly written) and then all the way down to crawling through IMDB boards/Reddit (essentially internet forums – and we know how these are. Have to wade through tons of shit to hopefully find 1 nugget of good info).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get any real answers/insight into questions, some serious internet investigation would have to take place. Sometimes you’d find a decent answer on Wikipedia, follow it up with a good comment in Reddit, then have to read someone’s take on a random blog post. Once again – a massive pain in the ass, and it wasn’t easy to share the end result with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a friend, I decided to build a new way to do this. We’re on V2 now, but in the meantime – to quickly test the general thesis of this idea (do people even care about reading more into film/tv shows?), I did an annotation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1dwjTCc&quot;&gt;“The Godfather”&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://poetry.rapgenius.com/&quot;&gt;PoetryGenius&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; shared with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://poetry.rapgenius.com/tv-movie-genius&quot;&gt;RapGenius&lt;/a&gt; community. The response was pretty awesome – got a lot of comments, messages, feedback, and views pretty quickly. Even floated over to popular posts on the home page for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was pretty cool to share the annotation with other people and see other people care about it. The annotation style on Rapgenius is not exactly how I imagine this working, but it’s close enough for a quick test. Going to continue working to finish V2, but in the meantime will do a few more types of annotations and share to see if it continues to resonate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out! &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1dwjTCc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Godfather” Annotation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expensive Headphone Review</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/01/04/expensive-headphone-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2014/01/04/expensive-headphone-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently got some higher end headphones as a gift. While they were awesome, I wanted to make sure I was getting my money’s worth, so I looked around. Here’s what I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been super big on headphones, so this was my first real pass at something nice. For the last few years, I’ve just been using whatever headphones came with my cell phone – most recently the iPhone 5 in ear headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iphone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iphone5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started to get into it, I realized I had no idea what I was reading about. Circumaural vs supraural, noise cancelling vs noise isolation – all meaningless to me. So I read a bit. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/which-headphones-should-i-get/&quot;&gt;Wirecutter has a great overview&lt;/a&gt; on the space, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Headphones#Types&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; is always good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case &amp;amp; Criteria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main use for headphones for work. Calls, blocking others out, trying to focus on what’s on hand, etc. From what I read, I knew I didn’t want another set of in ear headphones – I already had Apple for that. And supra-aural was no good, I had a pair a few years ago and they were uncomfortable. Was unsure about noise cancelling vs noise isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So came up with this list of things that were important to me &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blocks Noise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who travels and works remotely fairly often, I find myself frequently working in noisy places. Lots of coffee shops, airports, and even when I am in the office/at home, lots of people on calls. It can be super distracting and really suck. Apple in ear headphones do not suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comfort&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, I got a pair of supra-aural &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc0DB5&quot;&gt;Grado Labs SR60i&lt;/a&gt; headphones a few years back (gift) – and while the quality of music was amazing, they were not that comfortable. I found after wearing for a few hours, my ears would start to ache. Given the long amounts of time I have my headphones in, comfort was an important factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needs a mic on it. I’m on calls for a large part of the day, and being able to quickly answer calls without taking my headphones off is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I travel and move around from place to place a lot. Needs to be easy to bring around places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sound Quality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, should needs to be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a fair amount of reviews and guides on a variety of publications and product reviews on Amazon. The best article I found was this – &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-300ish-headphone/&quot;&gt;Wirecutter’s Best $300 Over Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt;. Went to try a few of these out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One note – There are 2 types of noise reducing headphones – noise isolation and noise cancellation. Noise isolation means the headphones just cover your ears. Active noise cancellation headphones means there’s a mic that listens to external noise and actively tries to cancel it. For noise cancelling headphones, you typically have a battery and a switch to turn on the noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc1H80&quot;&gt;Sennheiser Momentum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sennheiser.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;momentum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most acclaimed headphones I found were the Sennheiser Momentums. The reviews were great, and they look amazing. No active noise reduction. All around glowing reviews – the only real concern voiced online was that they weren’t very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to music in these were an absolute delight. The quality of sound was great. But while the sound quality was every bit as good as the reviews mentioned, the comfort issues were equally accurate. They earpads didn’t fit over my entire ear, and the headphones felt small on my head. It was immediately apparent that wearing these for long durations of time would be a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Sound quality is awesome. The look and feel of the product is even better. But the dealbreaker is comfort – wearing these for long periods of time wouldn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1fc2rKk&quot;&gt;PSB M4U2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/psb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;psb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were Wirecutter’s winner for best pair for $300. Active noise cancellation, and people praised the quality of sound. What was awesome was that you could use the headphones without turning noise cancellation on (unlike some others).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without noise cancelling, the headphones sounded nice. With noise cancelling on, they sounded great. The noise cancelling let you focus on the quality of the sound, which was amazing. Also, there’s lots of padding so they’re very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they are big and heavy. You can definitely feel the extra weight on your head, and they take up a lot of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: While the sound quality was great, the headphones were far too heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1cXfGLs&quot;&gt;Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins P7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bowers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bowers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These headphones look a bit different from what I’m used to, and I put them on with a bit of bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they are surprisingly comfortable. They fit over the entire ear, and they feel solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I wasn’t super impressed with the sound quality. It certainly wasn’t bad, but I like the PSB M4U2’s and Sennheiser Momentum better. These also weren’t noise cancelling, and I was trying them out in a noisy environment – I could hear pretty much everybody. Quickly scratched this from the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $399&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Expensive, looks a bit too special for me, and not as good as others in relation to sound quality or noise reduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1duompf&quot;&gt;Audio Technica ATH-ANC9 Quietpoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/audiotechnica.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;quietpoint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Technica headphones in general are very well regarded, and the general sentiment is that Audio Technica makes great headphones at a great prices. These in particular had active noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you put these on, you’ll notice immediately how little you notice. They’re really light and by far the most comfortable I had tried up to this point. The noise cancellation worked well – you could also use the headphones with or without it turned on, which was really nice. Sound quality was nice – on par or only slightly inferior to Momentum or M4U2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $285&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: Sound quality good and comparable to others. Noise cancellation better than PSB’s, and much more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1lO5KFa&quot;&gt;Bose QC15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bose.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bose&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister has these, so I did try &amp;amp; use these more extensively than the others. When I switched them on, I was amazed. These were incredibly good at cancelling out sound – proved when I was writing this post and I had absolutely no idea there was a group of people talking behind me. Also really light and comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as the Bose haters will note, the sound quality is a bit below average relative to the others. Also, these headphones only work when noise cancellation is turned on – so if your battery’s dead, can’t use them. Which sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: $299&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take: What these lack in sound quality is made up with amazing noise cancellation and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winner: Bose QC15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came down to it, noise cancellation and comfort trumped sound quality. The Bose headphones, despite the inferior sound quality relative to the others in this list, were by far the most comfortable comfortable its noise cancellation was far better than anything else. Also has a mic to make calls!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone like me – frequently on the go and working in noisy environments, Bose is the way to go. Else, if you’re buying headphones to really enjoy music in a quiet environment, I would go with something else - either the Sennheiser Momentum or PSB M4U2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps I Used in 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/31/apps-i-used-in-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/31/apps-i-used-in-2013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a href=&quot;http://parislemon.com/post/71774755194/the-apps-i-actually-used-in-2013&quot;&gt;MG’s post on the same subject&lt;/a&gt;. Thought it was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are mine. Tried to rank in terms of usage/importance per category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Asana&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tempo/Google Calendar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Google Drive&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dropbox&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hipchat&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;GoToMeeting&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jira&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Zendesk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Balsamiq&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep Time/Clock&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Google Maps&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Pocket&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Evernote&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Speedtest&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Draft&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lift&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Penzu&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Line&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Yelp&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;IFTTT&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Flixter (Rottentomates)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Yahoo Sports (Fantasy Basketball)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Square Cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Buffer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tumblr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandora&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shazam&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May need to update &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisyin.com/tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/a&gt;. Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Thermostat Review</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/23/nest-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/23/nest-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought my folks a Nest over break. The question I hear a lot is – is it worth the ~$300?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - Yes. It’s good for now, but not perfect. Review below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://nest.com/thermostat/life-with-nest-thermostat/&quot;&gt;Nest Thermostat&lt;/a&gt; is a ‘smart’ thermostat that learns from your habits to reduce wateful spending. Touting features like auto away (turning heat down automatically when you’re out), self learning (setting optimal temperatures itself) and more, it’s a pretty compelling buy. And not to mention that it looks awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation &amp;amp; Installation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you can use the Nest, you have to make sure it’s compatible with your house. To find out, you remove the cover of your current thermostat, go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://widgets.nest.com/compatibility/&quot;&gt;Nest compatibility site&lt;/a&gt; and check a few wires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old-thermostat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I had a W, Rh, Y, G, and another tying Rh to Rc. I emailed them in case (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:photos@nest.com&quot;&gt;photos@nest.com&lt;/a&gt;) and they were pretty quick (within 6 hours) to respond and confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the site, I was returned with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest3.png&quot; alt=&quot;diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was unsure of what to do with the Rh to Rc wire, so I left it off. Discovered later that &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-do-I-install-Nest-if-my-old-thermostat-had-a-short-wire-connecting-Rh-and-Rc&quot;&gt;it wasn’t necessary&lt;/a&gt; (aside – found a fair amount of people with the same question, so would have been helpful to include in setup instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest4.png&quot; alt=&quot;install&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation was pretty straightforward – turn off the electricity via circuit box, remove old thermostat, screw in Nest plate, plug in wires, and then put the Nest on top of it. 15-20 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it’s on, configuration was easy – it takes you through a few setup screens – name your Nest, set the network, time zone, default temp, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this was done, next was to link my phone. Created a Nest account on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.nest.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and it auto linked my account to my Nest based on the network. Again, pretty smooth &amp;amp; easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the Nest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although everything had been easy up to this point, learning more about using Nest was a bit lacking. Outside of learning by pushing buttons, Nest has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.nest.com/community/help-with-nest&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/thermostat/&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; page on their site. While these pages provided some info, I was still hoping to get into more detail on all their features and how to optimally configure/use it. There’s almost nothing useful in the box, and what I &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/An-introduction-to-learning&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; on the web wasn’t enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the cool features – &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/An-introduction-to-learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-does-Auto-Schedule-learn&quot;&gt;Scheduling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/What-is-Early-On&quot;&gt;Early On&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-does-the-Nest-Leaf-work&quot;&gt;Leaf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/How-to-read-my-Energy-History-on-the-Nest-Learning-Thermostat&quot;&gt;Energy Savings&lt;/a&gt; and more, are things that develop over time. To learn more, I had to look into a forum or community thread – it would have been helpful to get information straight from Nest – list of features, how/when to use X feature, when to check back in to make sure it’s being used properly, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this info is up front and center as opposed to hidden in support, users will better understand what Nest is doing and how to get the most out of it. While I understand the goal of Nest is to ‘set it and forget it’, it would have been helpful to spell out the features for users so they don’t have to go digging through the the forums to find the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize this is a fairly large upgrade from the standard thermostat in terms of aesthetic/usability – and although the UX is nice, I was a bit disappointed in the UI, both on the device and the apps (&lt;a href=&quot;https://home.nest.com/&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id464988855?mt=8&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt;). While you have to take the 2 1/2 stars and poor reviews with a grain of salt, the apps could definitely use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the one area that scared me a bit. After initially setting up the Nest, we left town for a day. Upon return, I was excited to turn on the Nest &amp;amp; pre-heat the house remotely – but the app said the Nest was offline. After getting back and checking – Nest having trouble connecting to the network because of low battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally unaware there was even a battery (thought it powered through the wall), I went online to figure out what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest5.png&quot; alt=&quot;images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found this on the support page and it &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/Intermittent-low-battery-or-connectivity-issues-with-thermostat-software-4-0&quot;&gt;lead to this article&lt;/a&gt;. With no steps to fix, had to search a bit more and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.nest.com/article/What-s-the-mini-USB-port-on-the-back-of-the-display-for&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; – had to recharge Nest through an outlet so we could use &amp;amp; reconnect in the interim (next up was &lt;a href=&quot;http://shaunmerrigan.info/site-news/nest-thermostat-battery-charge-problem-and-solution/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; if it didn’t work). Let it charge for ~1hr and set it back on the wall. Haven’t had a problem since, but the lack of clear steps for a resolution left me a bit uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While perusing the support pages during this time, I found a few frustrated people with Nest’s seemingly lack of care for support issues. With only a support email alias and no direct number, I can see why. While email only support is fairly common for startups, not sure if this is a good approach for home consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems like I’m not the only one with some issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'&gt;&lt;p&gt;huh. Got a &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/nest'&gt;@nest&lt;/a&gt;. PG&amp;amp;E bill is 3x higher than last month. Clearly it needs some learning ...&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Micah Baldwin (@micah) &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/micah/statuses/420271372980326401'&gt;January 6, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urg. &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/nest'&gt;@nest&lt;/a&gt; is playing up, needs a software update, and the web site doesn’t explain how to force an update to ver 4.01. Anyone know?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Borthwick (@Borthwick) &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/Borthwick/statuses/420756098761494528'&gt;January 8, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Still, Nest will need to better educate customers and ramp up support to avoid being blamed for problems it didn’t cause. Otherwise, customer issues like these could shake confidence in Nest&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href='http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/06/nest-4-0-firmware-battery-problems/'&gt;&amp;mdash; Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But if it's causing problems for even adept users like myself, this could be a big problem in the long run for the company.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.businessinsider.com/nest-thermostat-problem-2014-1'&gt;&amp;mdash; Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Nest-Learning-Thermostat-Generation-T200577/product-reviews/B009GDHYPQ/ref=cm_cr_pr_hist_1?ie=UTF8&amp;filterBy=addOneStar&amp;showViewpoints=0&amp;sortBy=bySubmissionDateDescending&quot;&gt;Another link to some pretty poor Amazon reviews (obviously, take these with a grain of salt).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’ve had a good experience with Nest and would generally recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear the Nest guys spent a lot of time building a beautiful product. However, the experience as a whole feels incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aesthetics and functionality of the product are amazing and undoubtedly a step up from a traditional thermostat. But as for continuing to support and help users maximize usage of the product after installation, Nest could use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By simply adding a detailed user manual so users know how they’re benefitting from Nest’s features and providing a better support site or line, they could dramatically improve the overall experience. Otherwise, Nest runs the risk of being perceived as an expensive remote control for your thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re into new toys and want to upgrade – Nest is perfect for you. But I think for now, Nest will remain an expensive toy in consumers’ eyes until it has spent more time in the market proving that it is worth the cost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Freemium Doesn't Always Work in B2B</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/21/freemium-doesn%27t-always-work-in-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/21/freemium-doesn't-always-work-in-b2b</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a follow up post to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1hxzntZ&quot;&gt;Building for the Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For startups, the business space may seem like a gold mine. There are problems everywhere you look, customers will pay you to fix them, and there’s not millions of other startups competing with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these attributes can make the business space attractive, not all problems are applicable to every business. Entrepreneurs must understand the types of problems they are solving in relation to the priorities of the companies they’re targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies are filled with problems. Productivity, collaboration, operations, hiring, legal, sales, support, etc. But depending on the stage of the business – early, growth, pre-IPO, public, etc. – each one will have different priorities (in regards to problems that need to be solved).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, take an early stage company – their focus may be marketing &amp;amp; sales. In this case, the priority is to find a solution to help them manage deals. A growth stage company’s main focus may be managing support – so they’ll be looking for a support tool. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to determine if a problem fits a company’s stage, simply ask – is this a C-level problem? C-level issues are problems important enough that a CEO/exec will prioritize it. Usually only then will it get solved in a timely manner; otherwise, it may not get solved in a time frame that you can stomach (or afford).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18MuCue&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18Muzyn&quot;&gt;Coupa&lt;/a&gt;, we made and sold an expense management solution – a web/mobile app that helped companies create, approve and reimburse their employees’ expense reports. More than making it easier for employees to capture their expenses &amp;amp; get reimbursed, our software streamlines the reimbursement process – helping companies reduce the operational cost of processing and managing lots of expense reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our solution reduces cost, we have to target companies whose priority is cost reduction. Typically smaller companies are more focused on the top line (sales), while larger companies can also focus on the bottom line (cost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get these large enterprises, our strategy (product, sales, marketing) has to reflect how they buy software – through RFP’s, direct sales, analyst reports, etc. We need an enterprise roadmap, the right messaging, and an enterprise sales team in order to maximize our ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our previous model – freemium/bottom up – was not the most effective way to reach our customer. While we aimed for large deals, this model attracted consumers and SMB’s – because the freemium model was akin to how consumers/SMB’s bought software, not how large companies bought software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for many of the SMB’s that we did engage – they sale either dragged on for too long or eventually petered out – because even though we had gotten into the business, that particular problem wasn’t a C-level problem or a business priority. Our strategy didn’t match our target customer’s stage or how they bought software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before you take the popular sentiment of building a freemium SaaS, make sure you understand the problem you’re solving and what stage of company is interested – and then build your strategy around that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building for the Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/14/building-for-the-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/12/14/building-for-the-enterprise</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago, I joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18MuCue&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt; – a startup building expense management tools for businesses and individuals. We were 4 years old, bootstrapped, small (3 full time + interns), ~85K users and ~150 paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time building for businesses. I studied and learned about building product for companies, how to sell, marketing, support, scaling, recruiting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 6 months later, we were acquired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcrn.ch/18Muzyn&quot;&gt;Coupa&lt;/a&gt;, a spend management company, to help run &amp;amp; build upon their existing expense management business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we started at Coupa, I thought I’d be doing the same thing I was doing at Xpenser, but just at a different company. The setting would be different, but the goals were the same – build the best expense management solution for the businesses. At the time we joined, Coupa was 6 years old, had raised ~$50M in venture capital, ~150 people, and 400+ paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong. Even though both times we were solving the same problem &amp;amp; selling to companies, the lessons I learned didn’t apply universally. At Xpenser we were selling to businesses; at Coupa, we were selling to the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a student of the startup game, both times (at Xpenser &amp;amp; Coupa) I went to the web to learn from founders/entrepreneurs. Both times I found little helpful information, and in many cases, what I did find turned out to just be plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of startup advice I found on the web was directed at consumer startups. And that made sense – for a startup whose customers are other businesses, you don’t want to keep gushing your mistakes in a public forum. That kind of information will kill you in a sale. Opacity and boilerplate press releases were safer than honest blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s hard to find good information on the web for startups to learn about building for businesses. For what I did find – there seemed to be a general misconception – B2B does not always mean enterprise. There is some gray area, but for the most part, there is a distinction between building for businesses and buidling for the enterprise. There are difference, and those differences should shape your strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After serving and building for all types of businesses at both Xpenser &amp;amp; Coupa, I’ve learned a bit about the space, and I’ll be sharing what I’ve learned here. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/DdF7n&quot;&gt;Click here to subscribe&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/10/19/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/10/19/leadership</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to get someone to follow you, even if only out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do people believe you have the interest of the company over yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do they believe you can execute?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have all 3, you’ve got it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Hard &amp; Not Getting Anything Done</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/27/pretending-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/27/pretending-to-work</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are hunting elephants, don’t get distracted chasing rabbits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;T. Boone Pickens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I’ve been a big inbox zero guy. I rigorously maintained all of my inboxes and other web services (pocket, feedly, evernote, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, if you didn’t manage your online services, they were useless. Then they were toys – fun to play with, but don’t provide any real utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was getting a fair amount of emails and I was able to manage. Since I started at Coupa, it shot up at least 3 fold and I was drowning in a deluge of emails. I couldn’t keep up. I needed a new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iqUG2_cmZ6I&quot;&gt;PandoMonthly with Chris Sacca&lt;/a&gt; (embedded below). An awesome talk all around – but the point that that stood out to me was the notion of offense vs. defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take an email inbox. An inbox is really just a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shellen/status/228202415789334528&quot;&gt;public todo list&lt;/a&gt; that anybody can put things on. You can easily spend all day ticking off your emails and it’s easy to feel accomplished and like you’re getting a lot done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s a false sense of accomplishment. By spending your efforts checking off tasks that anyone can give you, there’s no coherence around your tasks. You keep working aimlessly and doing everyone’s else’s bidding but your own. It’s the ultimate exercise in feeling busy, but not actually doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior, I was always impeccable at getting my emails done. I always emailed back. I always followed up at least 3 times. The more useless emails that I responded to, the more useless work came into my life. I didn’t realize any of this at the time – I felt like I was getting shit done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it fell apart with the addition of Coupa emails, I started trying to figure out a new way to manage all my emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when I watched the video below and it opened my eyes to what I was actually doing. I felt accomplished, but I was really just keeping busy doing work for other people. I was only making marginal – if any – progress on my own goals. That’s why every time I turned off my email and worked in a dark corner, I felt extremely productive. Otherwise I always felt like I was getting stuff done, but I didn’t feel like I was doing anything or making any progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I realized that in order to make real progress, I had to give up on the ridiculous notion of inbox zero. I took a step back, planned out some goals, milestones, and got to work. The endless slew of inbound emails were ignored unless they fit in with my set goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s been incredibly cathartic. Yes, my inbox is exploding, but I’m making real, tangible progress on the different goals I’ve set. I’ve been able to make more progress than before, find more free time, and everything else in my inbox is still going on perfectly fine without my response. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thought expands further than simply managing email. It’s a principle to remember in any situation – make sure you’re always playing offense. There are endless amounts of noise in the world trying to distract you. It can feel productive to work on clearing the noise, but it’s a waste of effort – and a futile one. The only way to truly advance on what’s important is to ignore the noise, buckle down, and push your goals to completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' frameborder='0' height='400' src='//www.youtube.com/embed/iqUG2_cmZ6I' width='532'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Step To Becoming A Leader</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/20/becoming-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/20/becoming-a-leader</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a leader?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leader is someone who drives a group of people towards a common goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaders come in all different flavors, but the best leaders all have a few things in common – they have a clear vision and they are the drivers that push it all forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does it take to become a leader? Charisma, salesmanship, product sense, etc. are all pieces of it, but not the key element. At the core, a leader is someone who simply makes good decisions for the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that everyone knows what a good decision looks like. People either explicitly know what it is, or they are able to “feel” when a decision is right. Intuition is still always there as a fail safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then why isn’t everyone a leader?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, most people don’t speak their minds. They stifle their own voice and default to the majority. The majority must know better, be smarter, have more experience, etc. This can be especially true if you’re in a group full of people smarter than you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become a leader, all you have to do is start speaking your mind. That simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking your mind is how you learn. You force yourself to have an opinion, take a side, and voice it publicly. If you’re consistently right, people will recognize this and you will quickly evolve into the decision making authority and leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when you speak up, you might not always be right. In fact, when you start to really speak your mind, there’s a good chance you’ll often be wrong. When this happens, it can certainly be easy to hide behind silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re wrong, people might call you an idiot. And in the short term, you might actually feel like an idiot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn’t matter. When you put yourself out there, you expose your actual thoughts. You create a voice for yourself as well as subjecting your thought process to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take in the criticism, recalibrate, and try again. You can tweak what was wrong before, and constantly iterate your thought process to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you say nothing, you never put yourself out there. By not exposing what you think, you never challenge your own thought process, your ideas, and your beliefs. It’s easier to hide behind silence than subject yourself to the risk of ridicule. Over time, however, those that speak out will continue to improve and others will remain static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After constantly interating and optimizing your thought process, you’ll start to hone your instincts and begin making the right decisions. By this point you’ll have a voice for yourself in the group, have confidence in your opinions, and have naturally evolved into a leader for your group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve typically been pretty outspoken. And while this might all seem like common sense, I found that once I started paying attention to myself, I realized I was subconsciously defaulted to the majority on a several things that I actually had an opinions on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught myself and changed my behavior, but I wouldve never realized that I was keeping quiet until I started to explicitly watch my own behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a shot, would love to hear thoughts or if you’ve had a similar experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Improve Your Work, Stop Working</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/01/sharpening-the-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/08/01/sharpening-the-saw</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I’ve been in a depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a mental depression, but a depression in regards to personal development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I define personal development as doing things that you enjoy working on in your free time. Not just anything, but things you actively work on to get better at without any external motivation to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve spent all of my time working on my day job instead of taking the time to do any personal development. Things like reading, writing, or working on personal side projects that don’t make any money :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By spending all of my time working, I’m actually getting worse at work. And I’m not getting any better at my personal interests. Doubly bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get sucked into work. They pay you. Projects are handed to you. You feel productive when you work on something. You know what you have to deliver. Strategy and goals are set for you – you just have to execute. Things are relatively straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often these factors lead people to spend all of time working. With non-stop work emails as the new norm and every email marked as &lt;em&gt;URGENT!!!&lt;/em&gt;, it’s easy to feel like it’s irresponsible to do anything other than work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with constant working is that while you might feel like you’re being productive, you’re only making incremental improvements. By constantly working on the same thing – you close your mind and limit your ability to think and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Most innovation comes from outside of the company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/allison-fass/tony-hsieh-zappos-growth-strategies.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tony Hsieh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Zappos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What we know about the brain is that the brain does not work on forming its connections while we are focused on the idea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;http://mixergy.com/course-cheat-sheet-deliberate-innovation/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debra Kaye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Founder of Lucule Consulting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to innovate and make real strides in your career/ life, it’s essential to lift yourself out of the day to day tactical work and just &lt;em&gt;do other things&lt;/em&gt;. Finish a book, write a blog post, volunteer, or work on a side project. Get out of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By spending time applying your mind to other problems, you can learn and draw inspiration from outside. When you are focused on 1 problem, you develop tunnel vision. Your thinking narrows, and your thoughts can get boxed in. When you venture outside and let go, you’re able to re-open your mind and see things in a novel way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, by developing other skills, you simply become a more valuable person. You learn new skill set, open your mind, and become a much more versatile thinker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a personal anecdote, I’ve found my best ideas come from moments where my mind is farthest from the problem at hand. If I get stuck on something, I’ll start writing a post or start working on a side project and the answer serendipitously strikes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty for me is finding the right balance. I’m particularly fond of the way Jeff Atwood describes it in his post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2009/03/sharpening-the-saw.html&quot;&gt;Sharpening the Saw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guy who stumbled into a lumberjack. The lumberjack is feverishly sawing at a very large tree. The lumberjack was sawing and sawing, yet going nowhere. The saw was about as sharp as a butter knife. So, he says to the lumberjack, “I couldn’t help noticing how hard you are working on that tree, but going nowhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lumberjack replies with sweat dripping off of his brow, “Yes…I know.” The bystander replies and says, “But your saw is so dull that it couldn’t possibly cut through anything.” “I know”, says the lumberjack, “but I am too busy sawing to take time to sharpen my saw.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if the post is meant to be read this way – but to me, working is the tactical action of sawing away at the tree. Personal development is the act of sharpening the saw. In order to maximize your efficiency, you must find a balance between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constantly re-assess yourself, and be ruthlessly intellectually honest. Spend too much time sawing away and you never make a real impact. Spend too much time sharpening the saw, and you never get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So force yourself to take time and do other things. Especially in startup, it can be hard to pry yourself away from all of the critical things happening. But make sure to take time every day or at least every week to let go of work and focus on building your own personal skill set and interests. You will end up serving not only your company, but also yourself much better in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Teams Succeed. Great Teams Fail.</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/06/24/the-best-teams-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/06/24/the-best-teams-fail</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started at my new job, I’ve been waiting for one thing – to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate failing. But I’ve been looking forward to it. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For our group to turn into a team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there’s a big difference between people that work together and a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people are simply working together, things are opaque. The flow of information is asymmetrical, sporadic. The group can often feel mercenary-like. Driven by self interest and/or fear. They very tangibly lack &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; in each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This yields subpar work. When there’s no trust, individuals act in self-interest. When people act in self-interest, the results of the group suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team is different. Things are transparent. People share thoughts, opinions, comments. Discussions become primarily strategic as opposed to tactical and consensus driven. The team moves from mercenary-like to missionary-like. Aligned by a single vision larger than any single person on the team. People &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the golden state. There is meaning behind the work. People are empowered and self motivated. Amazing things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class='twitter-tweet'&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason transparency is a such a powerful value for a company’s culture? It breeds trust, and trust is the foundation of great teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Joel Gascoigne (@joelgascoigne) &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/joelgascoigne/statuses/340499460696203264'&gt;May 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how to build trust? There’s 2 main ways – success and failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your team succeeds. You deliver a high quality product, you close a big deal, etc. You’ve proven that your team can do something right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call this ability trust. Whatever you did worked before, so make it work again. Morale is high, and you hope to boil down the last success into a formula and replicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ability trust is contingent upon success. It all works great when things are going well. But when things go south, this can quickly evaporate. People start pointing fingers, and fear &amp;amp; self interest takes over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ability trust is very ephemeral – quickly won, but also very quickly lost. Teams need a more sustainable type of trust in conjunction with ability trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite. Your team works on something together, and everything falls apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 of 2 things can happen. 1 – the group turns on each other – point fingers, spread blame, etc. A complete disaster. Or 2 – the team will defend each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not defend failure. But prove that even in failure, they trust each other’s decisions and will defend them. ‘Because of XYZ, we thought this was best. It was the best decision possible at the time. We’ll get it right next time.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are knowingly wrong and your team sticks up for you, it instantly creates a bond. It becomes larger than just work output. The team believes in your ability, despite the outcome. You’re free to take risks, learn, and improve as opposed to just trying to cover your ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good team will have one of these. But a great team will have both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team &amp;gt; group of individual contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust turns individual contributors into a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create trust, teams must survive either success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create long term teams, they must survive both success and failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Made to Stick</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/28/made-to-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/28/made-to-stick</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just finished &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/114Pvtg&quot;&gt;Made to Stick&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some quick notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is about how to turn your ideas into reality. Ideas are incredibly powerful– they are the root of everything we do. They can do something as simple as convince your friends to a restaurant you’ve wanted to try, all the way to getting somebody to quit their cushy job and help you start that company you’ve wanted to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But frequently our ideas get ignored. Months later after an opportunity has been missed or taken advantage of by someone else, you mutter under your breath, ‘I had that idea months ago.’ A useless comment – you failed to get the buy in because you couldn’t convey the value of the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miscommunication is defined as when an expert (someone who thinks abstractly) can’t communicate with a novice (thinks concretely). The book provides a framework to bridge that gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called the SUCCESs framework (a bit cheesy, I know, but bear with me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;imple &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;U&lt;/strong&gt;nexpected &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;oncrete &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;redible &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;motional &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;tory &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep it simple. Every idea can be conveyed in 1 simple sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example – Southwest Airlines. Their mantra is, ‘We are &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; low cost airline provider’. Nothing gets in the way of that. When people are coming up with new ideas, adding new things, changing things – they always go back to that single idea. Does this help us become the low cost air provider? If not, then the answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple, powerful, and succinct. Everyone can remember it and start to make better decisions based on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unexpected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t grab people’s attention, they won’t listen. If people don’t listen, you can’t get your idea out. You need to do/say something unexpected or contrarian to get people listening and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create knowledge gaps. Lead people down a road and pause – as they fill in the next part on their own – reveal something unexpected. It’ll catch them off guard and keep them hooked, with the added benefit of creating a platform for them to start coming up with their own ideas/thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concrete&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concrete details are how to appeal to the masses. But concrete details are a double edged sword – say too little and nobody knows what you’re talking about. Say too much, and the audience loses interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limit concrete details to 3 things – &lt;em&gt;associations&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;self interest&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;identities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associations are things people are familiar with. You can describe a grapefruit to someone who’s never seen a grapefruit in 2 ways – as either a fruit with a soft &amp;amp; porous skin with an edible pulp, or you can just say it’s a larger, bitter orange. Simple and concrete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2nd is self interest – what is in it for me. The audience wants to know why they should care. Use concrete details to describe and sell the benefit of the benefit. You’re not selling power drills, you’re selling the ability for the audience to hang up pictures of their kids on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last is identities. Who am I, and what would someone like me do? Play to people’s identities – learn what that group wants, and then describe it in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to be credible. Reference experts (Dr. Yin says don’t smoke), aspirational people/celebrities (Lebron doesn’t smoke), the antihero (this ex-smoker with cancer says don’t smoke), or yourself (I quit smoking after I found out I was getting sick).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='http://bit.ly/13Xah2e' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maslow’s hierarchy. The lower end is physical needs. The higher end is emotional needs. Take your idea from something serving the lower end of Maslow’s hierarchy and aim higher. The stronger the emotion, the stronger the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pegasus hall is an army mess hall in Baghdad. Imagein a mess hall – thousands of sweaty soldiers pouring into a dirty cafeteria. Soldier after soldier in line grabbing food from an assembly line and eating off of a plastic cafeteria tray. Doesn’t conjure a grand image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One cook realized there was something more. Meal times were not simply just eating. For the soldiers, meal time was downtime; they were recharging. If they didn’t eat well, they would be sluggish and unmotivated during the next mission. If they were took a nice break and relaxed, morale would be high and the would perform better on the field. Meal time wasn’t about food – &lt;em&gt;it was about recharging morale&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cook spread the word to his team. From then on, Pegasus was known for the amazing meals they prepared. Fresh fruit, perfectly cooked steak, and spotless mess halls. Cooks would go through buckets and buckets of fruit to pick out the good ones. Wade through pounds of bad meat to find good pieces. All for the same pay and with the same ingredients at other inferior mess halls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aim high on Maslow’s hierarchy. Serve a higher purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above are components of a good story. Good stories are how experts (think abstractly) communicates with novices (think concretely).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 types of stories. Challenge, connection and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenge - the classic David vs Goliath story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connection - the ‘Chicken Soup’ type of story. An emotional story pulling on your heart strings – ie Help this starving child in Africa, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity - the mental challenge. A story with turns and twists that challenges the audience to follow along and guess what is going to happen next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use these types of stories in different situations. If you’re about to go into battle, get your troops riled up by telling a challenge story. If you want people to donate money to your charity, an connection story is probably better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest barrier to doing all this successfully is the curse of knowledge. The curse of knowledge is when you know more than your audience and leave out important details because you assume they are already known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to get your ideas out is to become a great storyteller. The best part is you don’t have to create the stories. If you can learn to spot great stories and re-tell them, you’ll be golden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the SUCCESs framework to craft your story and get your idea heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell a &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;imple, &lt;strong&gt;U&lt;/strong&gt;nexpected, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;oncrete, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;redible, and &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;motional &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;tory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Learning to Fail or Failing to Learn?</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/23/learning-to-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/23/learning-to-fail</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Failure. It’s a daunting thing. People like to talk about celebrating failure. They champion it like it’s something to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that’s ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start off — I’m a big proponent of failing fast and making mistakes. I think it’s a great learning tool. As it goes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Good judgement comes from experience. And experience comes from bad judgement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some people talk about failure as if it deserves the merits of success. I don’t agree with that. While I believe failure certainly is a prerequisite to success, I don’t think it is an indicator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing makes me nauseous. It sucks. It’s embarrassing. You fail because you were wrong, because didn’t try hard enough, or because you just aren’t good enough. Failing is a direct reflection of your ability. So when you fail, it means you suck. And that sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I juggle between two thoughts. 1 — I fail because I’m trying new things I’m uncomfortable with, moving forward and learning. 2 — I fail because I suck. I didn’t think it through carefully enough, and it’s a symptom of a bigger problem. To be honest, I’m not sure which is true. (Although I think I know the answer ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can say is that I learn by doing. Some people like to think through a million scenarios before deciding on anything. I act, and then improve iteratively. To me, thinking and theory are great — but there is no teacher like experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I move faster than others. As another result, I’m usually the first to make mistakes and break things. And get in trouble. But I also typically learn at the highest velocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest part for me is not letting the fear of more failures become the driver. It’s easy to crawl into a hole and pity yourself. Hope time will wash it all away. It doesn’t, and by staying in the hole, you make it harder to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to overcome the fear and the failure is to move on. Move forward, be bold and make the best of what is remaining. Oftentimes I’m able to rise out of the gutter and succeed just by acting as if my prior mistake was totally insignificant. Inside, the mistake eats at me day by day until I’m able to drown it out with a resouding success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let victory wash away the stench of failure, not time or pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a struggle, and I’m hoping to get better at it. I often wonder if I should be more concerned about failing less or learning to overcome the inevitable failure better. I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Thing You Need to Succeed &amp; Be Happy</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/09/the-only-thing-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/05/09/the-only-thing-you-need</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been driving up to LA more often (I’m in San Diego). I hate the drive, so I usually throw a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/10cuVtN&quot; title=&quot;PandoMonthly&quot;&gt;PandoMonthly&lt;/a&gt; talk into my car to help pass time. They’re all spectacular, but one that continues to stick out is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/15q6s8T&quot; title=&quot;Fireside Chat with Ben Horowitz&quot;&gt;Ben Horowitz chat&lt;/a&gt;. The whole thing is awesome — but one quote in particular resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The number one thing we look for in an entrepreneur is courage. Aristotle said that courage is the first virtue. Reason is, if you don’t have that — you don’t have any virtue. All the other things — honesty, integrity — they don’t get activated unless you have courage. It’s easy to be honest — unless it’s going to cost you your job, your marriage, or something else that you care about. Then it’s hard to be honest. So without courage, and you don’t have anything. You’re a zero character person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It struck a chord with me. Courage really is the cornerstone of everything. You always start with raw courage, and build up from there. Without it, your character is ephemeral — constantly fluctuating and adapting to the situation. Sometimes low quality, sometimes medium, probably never high. There’s no concept of yourself. You’re merely trying to fit in instead of injecting your own flavor. Zero character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need courage. Otherwise you can’t be successful or happy. Real success requires being innovative and original. You can’t do that through imitation. Without courage, you try and fit in through imitation. And by definition, a copycat is always 2nd to originality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you won’t be happy. You’re constantly trying to fit in, instead of being yourself. You ignore things that bother you, and you start to build resentment. Ultimately, that becomes destructive — you burn out and stop caring about your work quality, environment, relationships, etc. And since work takes up most of our working hours, you can’t be happy if you’re unhappy at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when you are courageous, everything seems to magically align. When I say courageous, I mean — speak up when you think something is wrong. Ask questions, have an opinion, do what you think is right. Don’t worry about what the norm is or what other people will think. Be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might step on some toes. You might piss some people off. They’ll get over it. In the long run, people will respect you for having an opinion and being honest. You’ll develop a unique reputation and maybe even make some friends. But regardless, you’ll be unique and have some character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, being courageous is easy — you just have to act like yourself all the time. It’s very natural, easy, and stress free. You maximize learning and minimize regret. If you disagree with everyone and are vocal about it — you’re either wrong and end up learning, or you’re right and look like a genius. There is no losing outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be courageous, live your life. It’s the surest way to be happy and successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' frameborder='0' height='400' src='//www.youtube.com/embed/sqI7fa04atc' width='532'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>51 Ways to Become World Class</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/04/21/51-ways-to-become-world-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/04/21/51-ways-to-become-world-class</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stumbled across this a few days ago. Really good stuff, so wanted to re-post it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know what you want. Clarity is power. And vague goals promote vague results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that every problem has a solution. Maybe you just can’t see it. Yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Age of Dramatic Distraction, the performer who focuses the best wins the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before someone will help you, you need to help them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become the most passionate person you know. It’ll be contagious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know more about your craft/the work you do than anyone who has ever done the work you do…in the history of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join The 5 am Club. Your most valuable hours are 5am-8am. They have the least interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devote yourself to learning something new about your field of mastery every day. Success belongs to the relentless learners. Because as you know more, you can achieve more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that when you transform your fitness, you’ll transform your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t check your mobile when you’re meeting with another person. It’s rude. And rude people don’t reach world-class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you do what scares you, you take back the power that you gave to the thing that scared you. And so you become more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem is only a problem if you make the choice to see it as a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop being a victim. Your business and personal life was made by you. No one else is responsible. To make it better, make better choices. And new decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lead without a title. Don’t wait to get a position to stand for excellence, peak quality and overdelivery on every expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your own style. Be an original. Every superstar differentiated themselves from The Herd. And marched to their own drumbeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that when you play small with your success, you betray your potential. And the birthright you were born under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat less food and you’ll get more done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you become more successful, stay really really hungry. Nothing fails like success. Because when you’re successful, it’s easy to stop outlearning+outOverDelivering+outthinking and outexecuting everyone around you. (Success is Beautiful. And dangerous).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not overprepared, you’re underprepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only level of great manners to play at is “Exceedingly Polite”. In our world, this alone will make you a standout. And differentiate you in your marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that the moment you think you’re a Master, you lose your Mastery. And the minute you think you know everything, you know nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To double your results, double your level of execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invest in your personal and pro development. All superstars do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get this year’s best Targets of Opportunity down onto a 1 Page Plan. Then review it every morning while the rest of the world sleeps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t get lucky. You create lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you push through a difficult project, you don’t get to the other side. You reach The Next Level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile. And remember to inform your face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend time in solitude every day. Your best ideas live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debrief on how you lived out your day every night in a journal. This will not only record your personal history, it will make you uber-clear on what you’re doing right and what needs to be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your not being criticized a lot, you’re not doing very much. Ridicule is the price of ambition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a monomaniacal focus on just a few things. The secret to productivity is simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the results very few people have, be strong enough to do what very few people are willing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest. Recover. It’ll make you stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy a smaller TV and build a larger library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that the bigger the goal, the stronger a person you must become to achieve that goal. So goal-achieving is a superb practice for character-building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food fuels your body. Learning feeds your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t ask for respect. Earn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish what you start. And always end strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In business, don’t play to survive. Play to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protect your good name. It’s your best asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that words have power. Use the language of leadership versus the vocabulary of a victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give more than you take. The marketplace rewards generosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that if it’s not messy, you’re not making progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be a hero to a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In business, aim for iconic. Go for legendary. Make history by how awesome you are at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don’t confuse activity with productivity. Many many people are simply busy being busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your doubts are liars. Your fears are traitors. Stop buying the goods they are attempting to sell you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best anti-aging remedy in the world is working really hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World-Class performers have no plan B. Failure just isn’t an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the power to change the world—one brave act and one person at a time. Please use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally discovered via a Quora blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/12JvhH0&quot;&gt;Musings of a Start-up Guy&lt;/a&gt;, which was a re-post of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/12Jvqu3&quot;&gt;Robin Sharma’s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Coupa!</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/04/17/hello-coupa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/04/17/hello-coupa</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve just been acquired by Coupa. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/XQq6aK&quot;&gt;read about it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I can speak for the whole team when I say that we’re all incredibly excited. There’s something really special going on at Coupa, and I’m excited to help Coupa continue to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goodbye Xpenser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/xpenseroffice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goodbye Xpenser!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello Coupa!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Coupa2013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hello Coupa!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use The Web</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/25/how-i-use-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/25/how-i-use-the-web</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently people have been asking how I use the web. Not sure why, but thought I’d write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use the web to get better at things I’m bad at. These are the apps that help me. All are free (some with paid options).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that are important to me are health, finances, productivity, reading, writing, thinking, and self reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meal Tracking – &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14ipM6q&quot;&gt;My Fitness Pal&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve tried a few and they have the best food database. Easy to log, create custom foods, and repeat common foods. At the end of each day they tell you “If you ate like this every day, you would weight X”, which is a nice reminder (although it never goes down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exercise – I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14ipSLd&quot;&gt;Sworkit&lt;/a&gt; in the mornings I’m too busy (or too lazy) for a real workout to give me a quick routine based on what I want to focus on and how much time I have. When I do have time to run, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/YP0aGv&quot;&gt;Runkeeper&lt;/a&gt; is the best. Also since I live a pretty sedentary lifestyle (&lt;a href=&quot;http://chriseyin.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/standing-desk/&quot;&gt;hopefully this will change it&lt;/a&gt;), I also use &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14ipSeh&quot;&gt;Moves&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a beautiful pedometer – helps me remember to get out and move a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep – &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14ipXhP&quot;&gt;Sleep Timer&lt;/a&gt; is amazing. Developed by the prodigies at Azumio, Sleep Timer gradually sounds an alarm when you’re in a lighter sleep so you wake up more naturally as opposed to being interrupted by an alarm during REM sleep. Also provides metrics on sleep patterns – average sleep time, duration, efficiency, and more. Really cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Task Management – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asana.com&quot;&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt;. It is the best, and I’ve tried them a bunch of them. It’s light, fast, and easy to use. Downside is their mobile app sucks right now. Mobile is for smaller on the go tasks(essentially chores), so in its place I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14ipWdP&quot;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt;. It keeps Asana clean, and when I get a free moment I’ll just run through a few Todoist tasks to feel good about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calendar – &lt;a href=&quot;http://calendar.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; is my default web calendar and is viewed on the phone through &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/YP0lBE&quot;&gt;Sunrise&lt;/a&gt;. Although as of late I’ve been trying out &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14iq2lT&quot;&gt;Tempo&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s not half bad — Sunrise looks better, but Tempo can auto dial conference call passcodes. Which is pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News – I have a pretty long list of blogs and news sites that I keep in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14iq512&quot;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve spent years building this list, and it is my primary source of news consumption. That’s why I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://chriseyin.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/trust-in-a-consumer-business/&quot;&gt;slightly annoyed about Google Reader getting axed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curated – &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14iq90w&quot;&gt;Quibb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.svbtle.com&quot;&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, in that order. Save all the good articles in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getpocket.com&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; for reference. Questions/discussions are directed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.branch.com&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books – I have an enormous backlog of things to read on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.com/w/14VFOBTRXIMDJ&quot;&gt;Amazon Reading List&lt;/a&gt;. I pick a book from there every once in a while (a long while) and throw it on the Kindle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal – I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14iqh00&quot;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of all personal expenses. Really easy to use, integrates well with banks, and nice graphs. The best feature is budgets — easy to set and stay within my limits every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work – I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xpenser.com&quot;&gt;Xpenser&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of work related expense (mainly purchases and time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/YP0y7H&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;. It’s easy to use and version control is really nice. I can quickly jot down some thoughts – edit, edit, edit – and then go back to see how my thoughts have progressed. Plus it just looks and feels great. Once I’m done, I copy and publish with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. Although now I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always jotting down ideas and thoughts on my phone. I need &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/14iqlNB&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for that. Easy to use and syncs across all devices. I take all of my ideas/observations from the week, cut the crappy ones (so almost all of it), and then save in a Google Doc for long term tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self Improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vocab – I try to learn new words on a regular basis. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/10tTCBz&quot;&gt;Evernote Clearly&lt;/a&gt; to read on the web and save words I don’t know with highlighter. The ones I actually want to learn go into &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/YP0CEF&quot;&gt;StudyBlue&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just flash cards — easy to use and they have a nice mobile app so I can quiz myself on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals &amp;amp; Progress – I write down a single goal in Google Docs every week and then at the end of the week mark it either red (0%), yellow (somewhat done), or green (100% complete). The same for the month and the year. Daily habits that I’m trying to form go in &lt;a href=&quot;http://lift.do&quot;&gt;Lift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journal – I like to keep a trail of my thoughts for self reflection, and that’s done in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.penzu.com&quot;&gt;Penzu&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t love it, but at this point I’m too invested in it to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calls – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skype.com&quot;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; is still the predominant method. I hate it, but I have to use it. Google Voice for phone calls, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/YP0Hbo&quot;&gt;Viber&lt;/a&gt; for international calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.join.me&quot;&gt;Join.me&lt;/a&gt; for screen sharing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uberconference.com&quot;&gt;UberConference&lt;/a&gt; for conference calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage - Drive, Dropbox, and Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other: Sublime, S3, Heroku, Chrome, Twitter, Pandora, Cloudtab, Google Dictionary, Honey, Buffer, Bitly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Desk</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/24/standing-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/24/standing-desk</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setup the standing desk yesterday. Pretty cool, cost $35 and took ~30 min to build. Really easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/standingdesk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;standingdesk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still breaking it in, can only stand for 3-4 hours at at time before my back starts giving out, but will continue working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would recommend it if you spend most of your day sitting down. If interested, &lt;a href=&quot;http://iamnotaprogrammer.com/Ikea-Standing-desk-for-22-dollars.html&quot;&gt;instructions here&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alphacolin&quot;&gt;Colin of Customer.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust in a Consumer Business</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/21/trust-in-a-consumer-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/21/trust-in-a-consumer-business</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found myself trying out a few of &lt;a href=&quot;http://on.mash.to/Xt809o&quot;&gt;Evernote’s other apps&lt;/a&gt; today (&lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/clearly/&quot;&gt;Clearly&lt;/a&gt; is amazing btw). Despite zero initial interest, necessity, coupled with bad reviews, I still managed to say eh, screw it — and download a few. I figured — it’s Evernote, they usually do cool stuff. I’ll give them a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/16M7f1O&quot;&gt;Keep&lt;/a&gt;, Google’s new Evernote competitor. While I know very little about Keep, I knew that I had no intention of learning more. It was a strange feeling, given that I have historically been a Google groupie. I’m usually all over their new products and defend shitty ones. After all, they make great stuff and give it away for free! Plus, since most of the web tools I use are already built by Google, it almost always makes more sense to go Google (even if I’m already invested in a competitor) — single login, they already know me, integrates well with other Google services, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no more. Because of Reader. Every time I use a Google application now, I wonder — are they going to shut this down on a whim? They’ve always been the company that didn’t do that — they built incredibly cool products and they gave them away all for free. Even things that you were pretty sure couldn’t make money. That was the magic of Google. You know they’re using your data — but you don’t care. There’s an inherent trust. You actively opt in to sending back data, sending feedback in, etc. Because you trust that they’ll use that data to build something that makes your life better. Sure, they use your info to make some money — but who cares? It’s not malicious — their products add so much value, and they’re not evil, right? And it’s largely been true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in a consumer driven business where you’re using people’s personal information to profit, trust becomes your most important currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they’ve lost my trust. Unceremoniously shutting down Reader to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/XtcFYX&quot;&gt;focus&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/XtcFYX&quot;&gt;they called it spring cleaning&lt;/a&gt;) was a major blow to their brand. And I’m not the only one that feels this way – &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/16M7Alf&quot;&gt;Om wrote a great post&lt;/a&gt; about it, and there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://oreil.ly/XtabcT&quot;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/16M6plT&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; as well. I don’t trust them anymore and I won’t invest my time into another Google product and subsequently have to worry about it surviving another bout of spring cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Google Reader</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/18/goodbye-google-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/18/goodbye-google-reader</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After closing the last work related tab on my browser the other day, I fired up Google Reader to catch up on some news and browse through the latest posts. Ironically, the first thing I saw was this: &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2013/03/13/google-kills-google-reader-will-go-offline-on-july-1-2013/&quot;&gt;Google Kills Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now while I lament the passing of Google Reader (and there’s tons of good stuff on why (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.calbucci.com/2013/03/google-is-about-to-learn-tough-lesson.html&quot;&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A25VgNZDQ08&quot;&gt;watch here&lt;/a&gt;), I’m not here to complain. I’m fully aware that Google could not care less about how I feel about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, If you’re as dependent on your RSS reader as I am, then what matters is finding a replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feedly.com&quot;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getprismatic.com&quot;&gt;Prismatic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msgboy.com/index.html&quot;&gt;MsgBoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theoldreader.com/&quot;&gt;The Old Reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feedspot.com&quot;&gt;Feedspot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netvibes.com&quot;&gt;NetVibes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsblur.com&quot;&gt;NewsBlur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reederapp.com&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5990456/google-reader-is-getting-shut-down-here-are-the-best-alternatives&quot;&gt;LifeHacker&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now while I’m typically a pretty cheap guy, Google Reader was used so frequently and was such an important part of my day that I am perfectly happy spending a few dollars to get a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ideal requirements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web based&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List style feed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seamless transfer from Google Reader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team that seems they care enough about RSS that they’re not just going to up and quit. (God forbid I have to go through this again!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magazine style feed option (I subscribe to a few design feeds, and I like to browse through the images for inspiration from time to time)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar interface (Learn how to use something new? Ridiculous!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one I found was Feedly. A quick search brought it up (they already had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.feedly.com/2013/03/14/google-reader/&quot;&gt;blog post on it&lt;/a&gt;! Impressive), and I was already familiar with Feedly – I tried it out when I was looking for a free RSS reader on my phone (did I mention I’m a cheap bastard?). Turns out it actually works pretty well – looks better than Google Reader, they can do a list based feed and magazine style, their transfer from Google Reader was nice, plus it was on the web and free. It wasn’t perfect, but it checked the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other one everyone was raving about on Twitter was Prismatic. So I logged in, created an account, poked around, and left. It looked nice, but I thought they were trying to do a bit too much. While others users might need a place to discover news, I just need something that will take my Google Reader feed. Prismatic gave me too much, and couldn’t figure out how to import in my Google Reader account. (to their credit, the founder responded to my complaint immediately and told me how – it’s actually pretty easy). Still, was a bit too much for me and I couldn’t replicate the feed to what I needed – organizing feed list style by folders and viewing by folder/subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MsgBoy just didn’t work for me. The Old Reader wasn’t allowing any importing (due to to large amounts of traffic). I ended up really liking Feedspot and Netvibes as well (looked and felt just like Google Reader), but Feedly did too, and Feedly looked a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the paid options – Newsblur and Reeder. I would love to have paid for Reeder. But I need it to be on the web! So regrettable, had to axe this one as well. And despite all the hype, just really didn’t like Newblur’s interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, ultimately I’m settling for Feedly (for now!) Seems to fit all of the criteria above best, and they have a nice mobile app to top it off. It seems to be the easiest way to continue living in a post Google Reader world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn you, Google. You selfish bastards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Hard Drive Free</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/15/living-hard-drive-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/15/living-hard-drive-free</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After switching machines every 2 months for the better part of a year, I finally bought a permanent laptop. However, after constantly changing machines, this whole experience has made it very difficult for me to keep track of my desktop files — I have folders, files, things downloaded from the web (books/docs/music/films) — and then when I’m forced to a new machine, I have to consolidate all of my desktop files onto a flash/hard drive, and then put it on my new machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this doesn’t sound that bad, when you take one disorganized group of folders and then add another group of disorganized folders to it (often with similar names), and then do it 6 or 7 times, things can start to get messy. For example, I’ll look for a PDF I downloaded — I know it was in my reading folder, but I’ll have to check Desktop/Machine1/Reading, Desktop/Machine2/Reading, Desktop/Machine3/Reading and so on to find it. And that can get cumbersome when you’re doing it all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I got my new computer, it was a chance for a clean slate — forget all the old messy folders, I can do it right this time. Only download files I actually need, organize them well, and keep as few files on my desktop as possible. As for the old files, I’ll throw them all onto an old hard drive under the folder ‘Archive’. You gotta cut your losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I failed. Ultimately, I started downloading things, saving files, and then creating folders to organize all of this as desktop clutter started to build. And then sometimes I would get that nagging suspicion that I’ve already downloaded this same PDF 7 other times on every other machine and just never got around to reading it. Which means I’ve not only been hoarding files &amp;amp; wasting space, but I’m also violating one main principle of life — not being selective enough about what I let into my life. Either I should’ve never downloaded it (demonstrating poor selection skills), or I should’ve read it already (demonstrating poor prioritization). Both are bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strategy in real life to be selective and minimize unnecessary clutter — lay everything I have out in the open. This way it’s easy to see out what I’m actually using and not using. I can’t hide things in a box in the back of my closet. If it sits there and I haven’t touched it in months, I throw it away. Pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to take the same strategy and apply it to my digital possessions. Minimize the amount of space so it’s easy to manage what I use, and discard what I don’t use. Also I wanted my solution to be in the cloud, because it makes the most sense. With the cloud, I’m actually limited by space (5GB on Dropbox is not a reasonable substitue for my 700GB hard drive), and it’s also accessible anywhere. I no longer have 700GB on my laptop, 1TB on my desktop, 200GB on my netbook and have to organize/maintain all of the different hard drives. My files are all in one place and they go with me everywhere. Machine agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to have to open and fire up a web app every time I want to access my files, that’s a pain in the ass. There needs to be a desktop client as well. With that in mind, the options are pretty clear — Dropbox, Google Drive, and Box. I use all of these already, and so I took a look at how I’m currently using the services, and crafted a way to use them efficiently and mold it to my goal of moving my entire hard drive to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drive has largely replaced Microsoft Office for me. I’m using it on a daily basis for everything – to create spreadsheets, track sales, write copy/essays, track ideas/thoughts/goals, etc. Almost everything I do can be traced back to some sort of Google Doc. So I cleaned Drive up a bit and kept it that way. Drive would remain my main tool and my first option for any type of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I looked through my Dropbox folder, I noticed that most of my folders in there are folders I share with other people. Mostly with me on the receiving end. While I do keep a bit of my own stuff in there, it’s mainly become a repository for shared info that can’t be done in Drive (code, pdf’s, contracts, etc). For the files that are personal, it’s mainly on the go material — reading. It has become sort of a flash drive, but in the cloud. I only have 5GB’s of space, so I can’t have all my files live in it. But the files on it are easy enough to access (Laptop, iPhone, iPad, Browser, and all without connection as well) that I will usually throw a PDF of a book in there before a flight or something. The added benefit is that everyone else uses it, so it’s easy to share files and pass around information. Since it’s only 5GB it can get of control pretty quickly if you have a lot of shared material, I’m going to try to keep it fairly ephemeral. Only books, music, documents, etc. that I need right now will be in there. Immediate consumption. It will conserve space, limit options and increase focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I have Box. Pretty similar to Dropbox, except I have 50GB of space on there. It’s enough space to amass a good amount of stuff without quickly running out of space. But it’s also small enough that you don’t have a lot of room to hoard. If you’re downloading things as quickly as I am, you can fill up 50GB in a short amount of time if you’re not careful. Essentially only pictures, good books, and archived documents that are necessary will be saved onto there. Only qualified files that flow through Dropbox will enter Box. This ensures that most things in Box will actually be worth keeping — I’ve actually used the file in some capacity (probably read it), and I decided that it was worth keeping. Once in a while, I’ll probably have to go back and clean it out, but with only 50GB of space, it will be pretty quick to see what I’m actually using and not. This way I can start to curate a very high quality repository of information, and since I’ll have actually previously consumed all of the information, it will become a digital extension of my own knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this funnel process — Drive to replace Office, Dropbox for keeping immediate files and sharing, and then Box as an archive of sorts — I can more easily reduce clutter and keep only the things that I actually need. In addition with everything I have in the cloud, theoretically, I’m making another step towards being truly machine agnostic. Which is cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: 5/23/2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a new laptop from Coupa the other day, and started working on it with next to zero setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave my Coupa laptop at the office and my personal one at home. One day at work, I needed a file and looked on my Desktop and — shit, new computer. But oh wait! Found it in Box. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/12/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2013/03/12/writing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I wrote a post called Experiments. I was going to shift the purpose of my blog to become an idea/experiments driven outlet. The supposed goal was to gain insight about my ideas, learn, and get better at writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all sounded great. This would create a purpose for the list of ideas that was accruing in my Evernote account. I would consistently learn about new things. I would have an excuse to write a bit more. Maintain a backlog of things to build. Checks all the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, it didn’t work out that way. I found that while coming up with good ideas on a monthly basis wasn’t that hard (and I use the word good pretty liberally here), finding the time to actually test them out was near impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing and coming up with the experiments to prove/disprove theories wasn’t hard. My drafts box is full of them. Google up some articles, look at some companies doing similar things, and then come up with some way to test the core theory behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the next step was what the tough part. I simply didn’t have time to build something and get real feedback that mattered every month. In the end, produced very little — a few half baked blog posts and web apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out vetting ideas takes time (big surprise). And turns out that it’s not worth vetting ideas for the sake of getting better at vetting ideas. I had no desire to take them anywhere — I was happy with current work, and wanted to finish it out, not jump into some other wild goose chase on whim. This prohibited my ability to really prove/disprove things — frankly, I didn’t really care. I wasn’t going to do anything with it. In reality, I just wanted something to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when I got it. I just wanted to write about something. Turns out I’m just bad at coming up with things to write about. So I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/essay.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham’s post on writing&lt;/a&gt;. His point is that you don’t need a well defined thesis or point to write. He compares writing to a river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river’s algorithm is simple. At each step, flow down. For the essayist this translates to: flow interesting. Of all the places to go next, choose the most interesting. One can’t have quite as little foresight as a river. I always know generally what I want to write about. But not the specific conclusions I want to reach; from paragraph to paragraph I let the ideas take their course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no explicit purpose. An idea strikes you — just start writing. Let the ideas come out and take you somewhere. You don’t need a well crafted plan of what to write and what not to write. You just let it go where it goes. A lot of the stuff you write might suck and never take you anywhere interesting (I know a lot of mine do!). But you’ll have explored a new area — and once in awhile, you might actually write something worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fanhattan UX Breakdown</title>
      <link>http://www.chrisyin.com/2012/09/26/fanhattan-ux-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.chrisyin.com/2012/09/26/fanhattan-ux-breakdown</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, my first time doing one of these things, but I love Fanhattan and wanted to throw my opinion in. So here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Product (iPad)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fanhattan is a catalogue of all film/TV media on the web that gives consumers a single point of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You search for things, Fanhattan tells you where it lives, and you can go there and watch it. Revenue is through affiliate marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Fanhattan ultimately wants from their users is what I’m going to call an Action. Action == Watching == Affiliate Revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user experience cycle goes from what I call Discovery –&amp;gt; Intrigued –&amp;gt; Learn More, then back to Discovery. Every stage should lead to an Action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_circle.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Fanhattan currently follows the cycle shown above, I think the UX has drop offs at certain points, and it would be nice to see a more fluid experience that gives me the info I need when I want it, encourages me to take action, and keeps bringing me back to Discovery. (Basing this off of personal experience, opinions may change if I were to look at user data.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus on the movie section. We’ll start at Discovery, move to Intrigued, Learn More, and then back to Discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_discovery.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Discovery section is currently broken into 7 horizontal panes in the top half of the screen. The panes are Smart Browse, Featured, Streaming, In Theatres, My Movies, My Friends, and Genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 panes is a lot to swipe through. And a few overlap, so we can consolidate. Smart Browse can already filter by Genre, so no need for a standalone Genre pane. In addition, My Movies is 3 personal lists; let’s make it all part of a dropdown menu associated with the “Me” button at the top (currently useless). Finally, Featured/Streaming/My Friends all help users discover films. Let’s group those together and call it Discover. We end up with 3 simple panes—Smart Browse, Discover, and In Theatres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Discover is now 3 panes in 1, we need to reorganize it. In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/PmcZW0&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, Chris Thun noted that discovery is 3 things—algorithmic, curated, and social. And it makes sense; the user starts with a large list of movies, and it gets more personalized as you move from algorithmic to curated, and then even more with social. Let’s reorganize the new Discovery category to reflect this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_discovery5.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with most general– the 1st filter should be All.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Most of the Streaming pane is new material. Group it into a filter called New. (Hulu/Amazon/Free can all be filtered in Smart Browse already)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add Popular– for movies trending amongst all users.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Re-label featured as Recommended. Take what the user likes and show similar films.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Last is Social, which is the currently the My Friends pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Smart Browse the same (it’s awesome), and re-sort In Theatres the same way we did Discover, from general to customized. We end up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_discovery31.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just 3 panes for Discovery. Browse. Discover, from general films down to user specific. In Theatres for up &amp;amp; coming. The same material, but no swiping, easy to navigate &amp;amp; understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when we tap on movie posters, Watch List, Seen It, Be a Fan options pop up. Let’s add Watch Now at the top so the user can immediately perform an Action when they see a film they like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intrigued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the user is unsure, they tap the movie poster and move to the Intrigued section. Currently for Intrigued, the bottom half of the screen turns into 3 columns (Photos, Watch Now, Movie Details). Tapping Discover pulls up a new screen (Learn More) with 9 separate panes (the first 3 panes are exactly the same as the columns in Intrigued).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_intrigued12.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user didn’t perform an Action in Discovery, and came to Intrigued to help with their decision. However, the current setup doesn’t help me make a decision – I need a bit more. And tapping any of these columns simply brings me to to the same pane in Learn More (and tapping the rating brings me to Movie Details)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless I was already prepared to perform an action, my decision ends up taking place in Learn More, rendering the Intrigued section almost useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic info I need is Summary, Cast &amp;amp; Crew, Ratings, &amp;amp; Trailers. Combine all the panes together, info on the left, actions on the right. Each section (Poster, Ratings, Plot Summary, Cast) should open a new window when tapped (ie tapping the critics/viewer meters will bring up the Reviews window). The user now has the requisite info and is led to perform an Action, or go back to the Discovery stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_learn_mores.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we’ve provided all the basic info a user needs to make a decision. So either the user really wants to know the the film before they perform an Action or the user has already watched the film and wants to learn more. By swiping to the right, the user moves to Learn More. Here the user can get click on News, Discussions (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/ThereWillBeBloodMovie&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/#!/search/?q=there+will+be+blood&amp;src=typd&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://getglue.com/movies/there_will_be_blood/paul_anderson&quot;&gt;GetGlue&lt;/a&gt;, etc), or watch Clips (&lt;a href=&quot;http://movieclips.com/&quot;&gt;MovieClips&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_learn-more.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the user who is still trying to make a decision, this window will tell them everything to actually watching the film. There is no more information we can provide– the user will now either perform an Action (Watch Now in the top right), or reject the movie and go back to Discovery (click off the window).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user who has already seen the film and wants to learn more has already performed an Action; we want to lead them back to Discovery. If they come this far for news/discussions/clips, I think it is safe to assume they at least mildly enjoyed the film. The user can then slide to the right and see an entire window of related films (categorized by Genre/Actors/Directors, etc) and this leads them back to the Discovery stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align='center'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/fan_related.png' /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user now consistently gains more info at every stage (Discovery, Intrigued, Learn More) and can perform an action at every step. And at the end, we lead them back to Discovery to start the cycle over, creating a continually engaging experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Fanhattan is still amazing – just my 2 cents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>